Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
Let's pray.
让我们祈祷。
Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
All right, welcome to the special edition of the Protocol Fellowship study group, the
好的，欢迎来到协议奖学金研究小组特别版，
Redux version of the intro to Ethereum by Mario here.
Mario的Redux版本的以太坊介绍。
So I think, I don't know, Mario, do you want to do a little introduction?
所以我想，我不知道，马里奥，您想做一点介绍吗？
like we did to the last one or just get right into it?
就像我们对最后一个一样，还是只是进入它？
I think we can say a few words about the study group quickly
我认为我们可以迅速说几句话
for people who are watching the recording
对于看录音的人
and then have a chance to catch the first one.
然后有机会抓住第一个。
Just to reiterate what we said in town hall, I guess.
我想只是重申我们在市政厅所说的话。
Yeah, welcome to the study group.
是的，欢迎加入研究小组。
Welcome to the Protocol Fellowship study group, everyone.
欢迎来到协议奖学金研究小组，大家。
Before we dive into the first talk, just to say, well, we are very happy to have you here.
在我们进行第一次演讲之前，可以说，好吧，我们很高兴能在这里有您。
We are glad that you want to learn about Ethereum.
我们很高兴您想了解以太坊。
We created this program based on our experience with Ethereum Protocol Fellowship,
我们根据以太坊协议奖学金的经验创建了这个程序，
which is more about hands-on development.
这更多是关于动手发展的。
And as people are starting to work on Ethereum, contribute to the actual software parts of it,
随着人们开始在以太坊上工作，为其实际的软件部分做出了贡献，
And we see that there is a big information gap, big education gap.
而且我们看到存在很大的信息差距，巨大的教育差距。
It's a pretty steep learning curve, even if you are coming from a programming computer science background to understand the Ethereum context.
这是一个非常陡峭的学习曲线，即使您来自编程计算机科学背景来了解以太坊的环境。
So we created this program to bridge the gap, to provide some educational materials and also just help you navigate on a certain path.
因此，我们创建了这个程序来弥合差距，提供一些教育材料，也可以帮助您在某个路径上浏览。
Like we still try to mimic this experience of a core developer, of somebody who is diving into the protocol.
就像我们仍然试图模仿核心开发人员的这种经历，即潜入协议的人。
we don't provide all the resources because it's up to you what you are interested in
我们没有提供所有资源，因为这取决于您的感兴趣
and what you what you want to learn about um we uh we have some basic structure of the program
以及您想了解的内容，我们有一些程序的基本结构
uh for the first uh five weeks uh we will have uh one call a week one one talk a week uh starting
嗯，第一个嗯五个星期，我们将每周打个电话一次，每周一次谈话
with this general introduction to the protocol today uh then uh we will cover the execution
通过今天对协议的一般介绍，嗯，嗯，我们将介绍执行
layer, the consensus layer, testing and security, and finally research and roadmap overview.
层，共识层，测试和安全性，最后研究和路线图概述。
This is the first five weeks, and in the second half, in the other five weeks, we will have two
这是前五个星期，在下半场，在其他五个星期中，我们将有两个
calls a week divided into two tracks, which are development and research. So, there are
一周的呼叫分为开发和研究的两条曲目。所以，有
two different domains, and you can choose one of those, or just switch between them, or just
两个不同的域，您可以选择其中一个，或者只是在它们之间切换，或者只是
just follow both.
只要遵循两者。
And those will cover, on the development side,
这些将涵盖发展方面
more deeper dive into the actual client code
更深入地了解实际客户端代码
basis and specification.
基础和规范。
And we'll show you how you can actually participate
我们将向您展示您如何真正参与
as a programmer.
作为程序员。
On the research side, you will learn
在研究方面，您将学习
about the future of Ethereum, about the improvements being
关于以太坊的未来，关于改进
researched, developed right now.
研究，现在开发。
So yeah, so this is the overview of the program.
是的，这是该程序的概述。
And with all of this, we provide, with these presentations,
借助所有这些，我们提供了这些演示文稿
we provide certain resources.
我们提供某些资源。
But our goal is to inspire you and show you all of these various domains
但是我们的目标是激励您并向您展示所有这些各个领域
and give you some starting points so you can actually deep dive yourself.
并给您一些起点，以便您实际上可以深入潜水。
There is a wiki, epf.wiki website coming with this program,
有一个Wiki，EPF.Wiki网站附带此程序，
where, as you notice, this program is coordinated.
当您注意到此程序时，该程序是协调的。
We publish these calls there to give you some resources.
我们在那里发布这些电话，为您提供一些资源。
But what we are hoping for is to create this wiki as an actual resource, actual knowledge base with resources gathered from all around the ecosystem.
但是，我们希望创建此Wiki作为实际资源，实际知识库，并从生态系统周围收集资源。
Because if you already started diving into some topics, you might notice that it's really scattered all around.
因为如果您已经开始研究一些主题，则可能会注意到它确实散布在周围。
There are various hackMDs, research posts, and papers, and so on.
有各种各样的黑客，研究帖子和论文等。
it's there is not like a single place to go for this hands-on um uh protocol topics and of course
这个动手的um uh协议主题，当然还有一个地方，当然还有
there are many great other wikis which we don't want to copy we just want to um have a context
还有许多其他伟大的维基人，我们不想复制我们只想有一个上下文
and links to the all available resources for somebody who is learning about protocol wants
并链接到所有正在学习协议需求的人的所有可用资源
to become a protocol core developer so uh yeah feel free to contribute if you get uh interested
成为协议核心开发人员，所以，如果您有兴趣，可以随意做出贡献
in one of these topics that I mentioned today or we will learn about it in coming weeks,
在我今天提到的这些主题之一中，或者我们将在未来几周内了解到这一点
dive into it, go about it, Google about it, find more details on it, and contribute it
深入研究，浏览它，Google搜索它，找到更多细节并为此做出贡献
back to the wiki.
回到维基。
Yeah, that's overview of the program.
是的，这是该程序的概述。
Took five minutes, hope it's not too long.
花了五分钟，希望不要太久。
Yeah.
是的。
Let's go through it.
让我们浏览一下。
So what did it forgot Josh? Should it add something?
那么它忘记了乔什？应该添加一些东西吗？
No, I think that is pretty sufficient. Just want to reiterate that most of the conversation is
不，我认为这足够了。只想重申大多数对话是
going to be happening on our Discord server. So if you aren't a part of that, please join the
将在我们的Discord服务器上发生。因此，如果您不是其中的一部分，请加入
Discord server. During these calls, we want to try to keep as much of the conversation to that server
Discord服务器。在这些电话期间，我们想尝试将其多大的对话保留到该服务器
as possible. There is a thread in the study group channel, there will be one for each
尽可能。研究小组渠道中有一个线程，每个线程都会有一个
of these different sessions that we can keep the conversations and questions and commentary
在这些不同的会议中，我们可以保留对话，问题和评论
on that thread so that everything is in one sort of centralized place and we don't lose it to the
在该线程上，一切都在一种集中位置，我们不会将其丢给
chat in the streaming platform. Yeah, and outside of that, Mario and I are here to
在流平台中聊天。是的，除此之外，马里奥和我在这里
to assist you guys through this process.
在此过程中为大家提供帮助。
And so if you have questions or comments,
因此，如果您有疑问或评论，
please feel free to ping us in that server.
请随时在该服务器中使用我们。
But yeah, looking forward to this presentation from Mario.
但是，是的，期待马里奥的演讲。
I've seen it a couple of times
我看过几次
and it just gets better every time.
每次都会变得更好。
Yeah, Josh seen it so many times.
是的，乔什见过很多次。
The next time it should be you doing it, man.
下次应该这样做，伙计。
Probably.
大概。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
Thank you so much, Josh.
非常感谢，乔什。
And yeah, you can use the,
是的，您可以使用
please use the Discord thread as Josh said,
请按照Josh说的那样使用Discord线程
because I might ask some question during the presentation and you should ask me questions,
因为我可能会在演讲中问一些问题，您应该问我问题，
so feel free to drop them in there so you have it all in one place. Yeah, and I should share my
因此，请随时将它们放在那里，以便将它们全部放在一个地方。是的，我应该分享我的
screen and show my presentation. Oh it's here, okay. You know if you can see it all well,
屏幕并显示我的演示文稿。哦，在这里，好吧。你知道你是否可以很好地看到，
i suppose so i believe that this works better than the gcp4 um yeah again by the way if you
我想，我相信这比gcp4 um yeaky又好
are here after monday fiasco um so sorry about that uh the problem there was not a server uh
星期一之后的惨败，很抱歉，呃问题没有服务器uh
it was not the software but the server uh because we just didn't scale the bandwidth and the cpu of
它不是软件，而是服务器，因为我们只是没有扩展带宽和CPU
the machine to so many people we are very thrilled to see uh so many people coming to this study
这么多人的机器，我们很高兴看到这么多人来参加这项研究
group so uh yeah excited to have you guys and excited to dive into the protocol 101 with you
小组所以，呃，很高兴有你们，并兴奋地与您一起研究协议101
so in this talk uh i will give you an overview of the ethereum protocol uh of its technical
因此，在这次演讲中，我将为您提供以太坊协议的概述。
parts it's the design uh and uh the way it's developed uh the way we work on this with
零件是设计，嗯，它以我们处理的方式开发的方式
with uh uh colleagues across many protocol teams and uh but i believe that to understand uh
与许多协议团队和嗯的UH同事一起
the protocol development what is happening on ethereum now and the way it was developed the
协议开发现在以太坊正在发生的事情以及它的开发方式
way it was designed you need to understand certain philosophy and uh fundamentals of it so uh i in
它设计的方式您需要了解某些哲学和uh的基本原理
the title you can see the prehistory because i want to talk also about the history about the way
您可以看到史前的标题，因为我也想谈论有关方式的历史
not just ethereum evolved but actually where it's coming from where um where uh these these values
不仅以太坊进化，而且实际上是从这些价值的地方来的
these uh these fundamentals uh uh have been have been created have been built um these ideas are
这些基本原理已经建立了，这些想法是
not new uh they are uh going all the way back many many years so uh to uh to have good context and
他们并不是新的，他们一直回溯很多年，所以呃，嗯，
to be able to grasp what is really important in the ecosystem i would like to dive all the way
为了掌握我想一直潜入生态系统中真正重要的事情
back to like 60s to you starting with unix creation then free software movement and uh
从Unix创建开始，然后自由软件移动和UH
of course the uh the donos don of modern cryptography cypherpunk movement because
当然，现代密码学Cypherpunk运动的Donos Don是因为
i believe that uh all of this and much more of course had impact on ethereum design on what we
我相信所有这些，当然还有更多的影响以太坊设计对我们的一切
how we use it here today and uh how we see the cryptocurrency landscape today
今天我们如何在这里使用它以及今天如何看到加密货币景观
so yeah let's let's start with that i guess let me just uh show you the presentation because my face
是的，让我们从我想开始，让我只是向您展示演示文稿，因为我的脸
yeah you don't need to see my face it's early morning here uh and yeah so let's start with unix
是的，您不需要看到我的脸，这是在这里的清晨，是的，让我们从Unix开始
uh for those who uh don't recall what unix is it's uh well it's basically two things uh
呃，对于那些不记得什么unix是的人，这是嗯，这基本上是两件事呃
first it's an operating system but it's also sort of a philosophy so uh unix has been developed in
首先，这是一个操作系统，但也是一种理念，因此已在
uh bell labs in this research institute uh since 60s 70s and it was created by uh richie and ken
UH Bell Labs从60年代70年代开始，这是UH Richie和Ken创建的
thompson uh if you recall this name then it's richie ken thompson they are creators of the
汤普森（Thompson UH），如果您记得这个名字，那是Richie Ken Thompson，他们是
c language uh and even before c the b language but today the c of course powers like everything
c语言uh甚至在c b语言之前
around us like the the operating system you are using the browser you are using it's all
就像您使用的浏览器所使用的操作系统一样
uh deep down c it's the today considered low-level language which uh uh which became very the most
呃，深处C这是今天被认为是最多的低级语言
important building parts of of the of the mother software and uh together with the c language uh
母亲软件的重要建筑部分以及C语言uh
these two people created the unix operating system not just them actually it was many many developers
这两个人创建了UNIX操作系统，而不仅仅是许多开发人员
researchers in the bell labs uh working together but this is the unix was designed together with
贝尔实验室中的研究人员一起工作，但这是Unix的设计
the c language uh in a certain way it uh uh when we talk about this unix philosophy uh what we
当我们谈论这个Unix哲学时，C语言以某种方式uh uh uh
mostly mean what is the uh major part of it uh is the modularity because the operating operating
主要是什么是UH的主要部分是模块化，因为操作操作
system is doesn't work in a way that it's a single program that tries to do everything
系统无法以一种试图完成所有操作的单个程序来工作
including the kitchen sink as we say um but rather than that it's uh separate modules separate
包括我们所说的厨房水槽，但不是那个单独的模块分开
programs each of the program does what is best at and has a clean interface which can connect
程序每个程序都可以执行最佳功能，并且具有一个可以连接的干净界面
to others uh if you are linux user today if you are maybe mac user today uh this is what is what
如果您今天是Linux用户，如果您今天是Mac用户，那么对其他人来说，这就是什么
is uh the core of your system uh if you use piping uh taking output you can take output of one
嗯，是系统的核心，如果您使用管道UH服用输出，则可以输出一个
program and use directly as an input to the other this gives you very powerful tools it's really
编程并直接用作对方的输入，这为您提供了非常强大的工具
empowering and for the user perspective it's a strong tooling but for the developers perspective
赋予用户的能力，对于用户的角度，这是一个强大的工具，但对于开发人员而言
it's very practical and secure because having the system divided in these modules rather than
这是非常实用和安全的，因为使系统在这些模块中分开而不是
just one program it gives you uh advantages so if there is an issue
仅一个程序给您带来的优势，因此如果存在问题
uh it's in one module and you can just fix that and it doesn't break rest of the system
呃，它是一个模块，您可以修复它，并且不会破坏系统的其余部分
and you can like encapsulate the complexity in these certain modules
您可以将这些模块的复杂性封装
the documentary link here uh you can you can find it in the wiki it's it's phenomenal i
您可以在这里找到的纪录片链接，您可以在Wiki中找到它是惊人的
I really recommend watching it it's just amazing how it is all the 88th Archive documentaries are
我真的建议观看它，真是太神奇了，这是所有第88个档案纪录片
able to articulate some maybe complicated topics but really clean really elegantly
能够表达一些可能复杂的主题，但真的很优雅
explained and you can see the people there Ken Thompson it's typing into pipes in in
解释了，您可以看到那里的人肯·汤普森（Ken Thompson）正在输入管道
the early Unix explaining how it works it's it's really beautiful to see and it's really
早期的Unix解释了它是如何工作的
it catches also the spirit of this environment in early 70s, I believe,
我相信，它也抓住了70年代初期这种环境的精神
because at the time, this institute, the Bell Labs, but also MIT or similar institutions
因为当时，该研究所，贝尔实验室，但也是MIT或类似机构
all around the world, actually, the early programmers worked in a way that, well, they
实际上，世界各地的早期程序员都以某种方式工作
collaborated. Also, the way that UNIX is created with these different modules and different
合作。同样，使用这些不同的模块和不同的不同模块创建Unix的方式
people working on their part, they need to talk to each other and collaborate.
他们从事自己的工作，他们需要互相交谈并进行协作。
They had always, you know, open door to their office, they could meet and chat.
您知道，他们总是打开办公室的门，可以见面并聊天。
And it was a strong collaborative environment where people who've been
这是一个强大的协作环境
building basically like one big thing together, but ultimately it was everybody's
基本上像一件大事一样建立，但最终是每个人的
doing their part, collaborating with each other.
尽力而为，彼此合作。
So I see a big part of this culture also reflect in the Ethereum development today on a much different scale.
因此，我看到这种文化的很大一部分也以不同的规模反映了当今以太坊的发展。
So yeah, I really recommend this documentary.
是的，我真的推荐这部纪录片。
It's like, it really well explains the Unix, it's a paradigm of computing that was invented more than 50 years ago,
就像，它确实很好地解释了Unix，它是50年前发明的计算范式
and we still use it today.
我们今天仍然使用它。
It's the way that we use computers today.
这是我们今天使用计算机的方式。
didn't get anything better like from from the teletype writer to the tty that you had you have
从电视作家到您拥有的TTY
in your shell today it's literally the same thing um okay and uh continuing with this story uh we go
今天在你的外壳中，这实际上是同一件事，嗯，嗯，继续这个故事，我们去了
to 80s uh with uh the dawn of free software so uh as i mentioned like people early programmers they
到80年代，uh uh the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the the Free软件
they collaborated.
他们合作。
Their software was, well, open,
他们的软件是开放的，
but it was because, well, to be able to run the software,
但这是因为能够运行软件，
to compile it, to fix it for your machine,
要编译它，为您的计算机修复它，
everybody just, you know, got the source code.
您知道，每个人都得到了源代码。
And these early hackers, as they called themselves,
这些早期的黑客称自己为
this was their way of operating.
这是他们的运营方式。
This was the way they collaborated.
这就是他们合作的方式。
But, of course, then in the 80s,
但是，当然，在80年代，
The commercialization of software comes, the military comes, and they create proprietary
软件的商业化来了，军队来了，他们创建了专有
software.
软件。
They close the software from its users, and now this has certain consequences.
他们关闭了用户的软件，现在这会产生一定的后果。
Proprietary software is, well, that which limits your freedoms as a user.
专有软件是限制您作为用户的自由的。
So now I would compare it to a house that you buy or have built,
因此，现在我将其与您购买或建造的房屋进行比较，
but to change something, to open windows, go to the basement and fix the heating, whatnot,
但是要更改某些东西，打开窗户，去地下室并修复加热，什么
you need to ask permission, you need to get keys from the basement,
您需要询问许可，需要从地下室获取钥匙，
from the owner or the builder or so on.
来自所有者或建筑商左右。
And the question is whether you really own the house.
问题是您是否真的拥有房子。
If you buy something like this and now you don't have permission to do what you want with it,
如果您购买这样的东西，现在您没有许可来做您想做的事，
But the creator is controlling it, whether it's really yours.
但是创造者正在控制它，无论它确实是您的。
Because this is what is happening with computers today.
因为这就是当今计算机正在发生的事情。
The computer you have in front of you, the phone you have in front of you,
您面前有的计算机，您面前有手机，
is a multi-purpose device, it's a general-purpose device,
是一种多功能设备，是一种通用设备，
it's a calculator which can calculate any number of operations in any way.
这是一个计算器，可以以任何方式计算任何数量的操作。
And you should be able to control it,
而且您应该能够控制它，
you should be able to tell it what you want to do with this machine.
您应该能够告诉它您想用这台计算机做什么。
However, if you run the proprietary software,
但是，如果您运行专有软件，
it's the developers, the creators of the software
这是开发人员，软件的创建者
controlling your machine
控制机器
and you don't really have an input.
而且您实际上没有输入。
You don't even know what's happening.
您甚至都不知道发生了什么。
You don't know what the proprietary operating system is coming,
您不知道专有操作系统即将到来，
whether it's calling home, sending your private data
无论是打电话回家，发送您的私人数据
or calculating pi on infinite decimal numbers
或计算无限十进制数字的PI
as I believe Windows Vista was doing
我相信Windows Vista正在做
or why it was so slow.
或为什么它这么慢。
Anyway, when we don't have the freedom, we are very limited.
无论如何，当我们没有自由时，我们就非常有限。
And this is what Richard Stallman realized.
这就是理查德·史塔尔曼（Richard Stallman）意识到的。
So Richard Stallman is often called the last hacker of MIT because he dedicated his life to this.
因此，理查德·史塔曼（Richard Stallman）通常被称为麻省理工学院的最后一名黑客，因为他为此奉献了生命。
He's now in his 70s, and all his life he only used free software.
他现在已经70多岁了，他一生都只使用免费软件。
He dedicated his life to keeping up this original hacker culture of being able to share the software.
他致力于保持这种原始的黑客文化，以共享该软件。
In September 1983, he started the GNU project and the free software movement,
1983年9月，他启动了GNU项目和自由软件运动，
which defined the four basic freedoms of software,
定义了软件的四个基本自由，
the ability to run it any way you want, to study the source code, to modify it and redistribute it.
您想要以任何方式运行它，研究源代码，修改并重新分配它的能力。
So he gave freedom to users.
因此，他给用户提供了自由。
And he's been advocating based on this all his life.
他一直在倡导他的一生。
The project that he started, the GNU project, might sound familiar to you.
他启动的项目是GNU项目，听起来很熟悉。
If you are using Linux, you might see GNU slash Linux,
如果您使用的是Linux，则可能会看到GNU Slash Linux，
because it's the operating system.
因为这是操作系统。
The goal of GNU was to recreate a Unix experience,
GNU的目标是重新创建Unix体验，
but in fully free software,
但是在完全免费的软件中，
because even though that people somewhat openly collaborated on Unix,
因为即使人们在Unix上有些公开合作，但
it wasn't truly free.
它不是真正的免费。
The GNU Project created licenses. If you go to GitHub, if you look for some of your favorite
GNU项目创建了许可。如果您去Github，如果您寻找一些您喜欢的人
programs there, you might see that it's licensed under GPL or the GNU General Public License,
那里的程序，您可能会发现它是根据GPL或GNU通用公共许可证的许可
which was created by Stallman, to give programmers a simple way how to license their program
这是由Stallman创建的，为程序员提供了一种简单的方法如何许可其程序
as a free software. And GNU Project created many core utilities. Maybe if you learned
作为免费软件。 GNU项目创建了许多核心公用事业。也许如果你学会了
c you used gcc the gno compiler collection which is probably the most used um c compiler
C您使用GCC的GNO编译器集合可能是最常用的UM C编译器
these days um and uh many of these core utilities is what we call uh shell the shell of the
如今，嗯，嗯，许多核心公用事业就是我们称之为uh壳的外壳
operating system but the core of the operating system was a big big task which was taking a
操作系统，但操作系统的核心是一项巨大的任务，正在采用
long time until an early 90s um linus thorvald's release uh the linux uh as a kernel of an
长时间直到90年代初，Um Linus Thorvald的发行
operating system under the gpl license and this could be coupled with the gnu shell creating the
GPL许可证下的操作系统，这可以与GNU外壳相结合
gnu slash linux operating system you use today so all of this was was really started by by storm
您今天使用的GNU Slash Linux操作系统，因此所有这些都是由Storm开始的
and i really really much recommend uh this talk from from tedx geneva where he really nicely
我真的真的推荐来自TEDX日内瓦的这次演讲，他真的很好
explains it uh puts it to context why it's important for software to be free and in ethereum
解释它会说明为什么软件自由和以太坊很重要
in all cryptocurrencies this is fundamental because the the the whole point of ethereum
在所有加密货币中，这都是基本的，因为以太坊的重点
is to give freedom to users to be transparent to be trustless and uh to do this we need to know
是为了让用户自由保持透明，以保持无信任和做到这一点，我们需要知道
what's happening there uh when i run the ethereum software uh i need to be aware that it's doing
当我运行以太坊软件时，那里发生了什么，我需要知道它在做什么
exactly what it's supposed to do it it adheres to the to the um specification and uh to what i
正是它应该做的，它遵守了UM规格，并遵守我
agree are the rules of Ethereum network. Then in 90s, there is the open source movement coming.
同意以太坊网络的规则。然后在90年代，有开源的移动即将到来。
Now you might notice that until now I only talk about free software, but open source is a different
现在您可能会注意到到目前为止，我只谈论免费软件，但是开源是不同的
part of it. The open source was created by some people from the free software community who
一部分。开源是由自由软件社区的一些人创建的
didn't like the branding, let's say, because free software kind of sounds like a free beer.
假设，不喜欢品牌，因为免费软件听起来像免费的啤酒。
it means Libre it means like you know free man free speech but it's not really good
这意味着libre这意味着您知道自由人的言论自由，但不是真的很好
word if you want to do business with it to you know give away free software so the open source
单词如果您想和它开展业务，请知道赠送免费软件，因此开源
was kind of a rebranding with also it's fundamental set it's it's it's values written out
有点像品牌品牌一样，它的基本设置是它的价值观
but the the open source movement talks more about the pragmatic side of it more about you know it's
但是，开源运动更多地谈论了它的务实方面，更多地是关于您知道的
it's good to be open because you can be more audited, have more security, you can bring
开放是很好的，因为您可以受到更多审核，拥有更多的安全性，您可以带来
more contributors and so on.
更多贡献者等。
So it's more like this business pragmatic approach, which is okay, but it omits it,
因此，这更像是这种业务务实的方法，这是可以的，但是它省略了，
it forgets the importance of the freedom there.
它忘记了那里的自由的重要性。
The whole point of this thing was to give the freedom to users.
这件事的重点是赋予用户自由。
So we say free and open source software or FOSS, that's where you see this acronym.
因此，我们说免费和开源软件或FOSS，这就是您看到此首字母缩写词的地方。
So for Ethereum, I believe all of these parts are important to be free and open source software
因此，对于以太坊，我相信所有这些部分对于免费和开源软件都很重要
enable collaboration and give freedom to users okay i've been i should i should go on it's a
启用协作并为用户提供自由，好吧，我去过，我应该继续
few minutes there um yeah um next up important important invention in 1976 important part uh
几分钟，嗯，嗯，下一个重要的重要发明，1976年重要的部分嗯
uh the new directions in cryptography this paper by defian hellman uh created a new paradigm in the
嗯，密码学中的新指示本文由Defian Hellman UH创建了一个新的范式
modern cryptography uh basically uh if yeah it's it's kind of basics for most of the people here i
现代密码学基本上是嗯，如果是的，这是我这里大多数人的基础知识
guess but uh this is the creation of the asymmetric cryptography or what we also call public key
猜猜，但这是不对称加密的创建或我们也称为公钥
cryptography or key pairs because before that uh before before this paper uh the encryption
加密或钥匙对，因为在本文之前之前的uh加密之前
was done only in a one way symmetric way so uh since um uh since the um uh i don't know caesar
仅以一种一种方式来对称的方式完成，所以自从嗯，嗯，我不知道凯撒
since the since since uh thousands of years ago people uh encrypted messages in a way that
自从几千年前以来
i take a message and i somehow scramble the the words i change the change the letters according
我听了一条消息，我以某种方式扰乱了我更改更改字母的单词
to some key according to some rules uh and if i pass this to the other party uh i need to give him
根据某些规则，对某些键，如果我将其传递给另一方，我需要给他
the ciphertext but also the rules the key how to decrypt it uh so we have a single key and single
密文，但也规则将其解密的关键uh uh，因此我们有一个键和单个密钥
encrypted text but in in with assamu decryptography we have we have a very strong tool which enables
加密文本，但在Assamu解密中，我们有一个非常强大的工具，可以启用
us to use one key we call it public key to to encrypt something and it's corresponding private
我们要使用一个密钥，我们称其为公开密钥来加密某些内容，并且是对应的私有
key which is only held uh by the by its owner uh to decrypt it only the private key can can can use
只有其所有者UH持有的钥匙才能解密其只有私钥才能使用的钥匙
a decryption but anybody can use the public key to encrypt a message this means that i can have
解密，但任何人都可以使用公共密钥来加密消息，这意味着我可以拥有
this public key on my business card in my in my website and anybody can send me an encrypted email
我在网站中的名片上的名片上的公共密钥，任何人都可以向我发送加密电子邮件
this was the dawn of encrypted emails uh mostly the implementation of pgp
这是加密电子邮件的曙光，uh主要是PGP的实施
um and of course if uh this rings any bell uh this is what all the cryptocurrencies use if you ever
嗯，当然，如果您响起任何铃铛，这就是所有加密货币都使用的
used ethereum if you ever used bitcoin you used public key or some derivation of a public public
使用以太坊，如果您曾经使用比特币，则使用了公共密钥或公众的某些推导
key uh as an uh as an address and the private key is what let you spend because of another unique
钥匙uh作为地址，私钥是因为另一个独特而允许您花费的东西
feature of this key pair cryptography uh which is digital signatures uh digital signatures are
这个关键对密码学的特征是数字签名uh数字签名是
mathematical proof uh which work in a way that uh uh with the private key we sign data we can sign
数学证明uh哪种方式可以用uh uh与私钥我们签署我们可以签名的数据
any piece of data it can be terabyte file it can be a simple message uh we sign this data
任何数据都可以是terabyte文件，它可以是一个简单的消息，呃，我们签署了此数据
and the signature is some uh mathematical proof which can be verified uh against the public key so
签名是一些数学证明，可以通过公共密钥验证UH
anybody who is seeing this signature and has your public key can verify that only the owner of the
任何看到此签名并拥有您的公钥的人都可以验证只有
private key could produce this signature this is the way as the transactions are done in interior
私钥可以产生此签名，这是一种方式，因为交易是在内部完成的
when i send a transaction i create a proof that i'm owner of this address and i'm signing the
当我发送交易时，我会创建一个证明我是该地址的所有者，并且正在签署
message that i want this amount of funds to be transferred here so um to another publicly to
我希望在此处转移这笔资金的消息，以便公开向另一个资金
another address right um and uh yeah this today we we take this for granted it's everywhere if you
另一个地址正确，嗯，今天，我们认为这是理所当然的，如果您
are connected using TLS, HTTPS in your browser here. That's end-to-end encryption using exactly
使用TLS连接，在此处浏览器中的HTTPS连接。那是端到端加密的确切加密
this technique. When you are using Signal or WhatsApp it's using some form of this
这项技术。当您使用信号或WhatsApp时，它正在使用某种形式
cryptography. So it's really everywhere today but that wasn't really true in the 70s and 80s
密码学。所以今天到处都到处都是，但在70年代和80年代并不是真的
when with the design of encrypted email with BGP, pretty good privacy tooling,
使用BGP设计加密电子邮件时，非常好的隐私工具，
This was considered dangerous, it was considered a weapon.
这被认为是危险的，被认为是一种武器。
So, the thing is that before the computers and internet spreading to houses,
因此，事实是，在计算机和互联网传播到房屋之前，
you know, to civilians all over the place it was mostly used really just by military.
您知道，对于整个地方的平民，它实际上仅由军队使用。
military. And now anybody can encrypt, anybody can achieve their digital privacy. And governments
军队。现在，任何人都可以加密，任何人都可以实现其数字隐私。和政府
didn't, I don't want to say they didn't like it, they didn't have framework, they just didn't
没有，我不想说他们不喜欢它，他们没有框架，他们只是没有
understand it, it was something completely new. And they considered cryptography a military arsenal,
理解，这是全新的。他们认为密码学是军事武器库，
a weapon which cannot be used by civilians, it has to be regulated, it cannot be exported.
平民无法使用的武器必须受到监管，不能出口。
it sorry many of these early cryptographers get into trouble because their open source free
对不起，许多早期的密码学家都陷入困境，因为他们的开源免费
software cryptography being being uh um uh exported so for example uh phil zimmerman the
软件密码学被uh um出口，例如，UH Phil Zimmerman
creator of pgp uh uh was under threat uh that he's going to be uh that he's going to go on trial for
PGP的创造者嗯，他正受到威胁，他将要接受审判
treason or something, because he created this email encryption, which is just mathematics
叛国罪之类的东西，因为他创建了此电子邮件加密，这只是数学
programmed in a software, that's it.
在软件中编程，就是这样。
And what he did famously, he created a book published by MIT Press, which contained the
他著名地创作了一本由麻省理工学院出版的书，其中包含
whole source code, including make files of the PGP version, like 2.7 or something.
整个源代码，包括PGP版本的制作文件，例如2.7之类的。
And then they could export this book.
然后他们可以导出这本书。
and the US doesn't have any regulation against exporting books.
而且，美国没有任何反对出口书籍的法规。
So now he protects himself,
所以现在他保护自己，
but we also can see that it's sort of a free speech
但是我们也可以看到这是一种自由言论
to just talk about the rules of mathematics
只是谈论数学规则
and write them in a language of a software
并用软件的语言编写它们
or literally the programming language,
或字面上的编程语言，
just a form of language, right?
只是一种语言，对吗？
So there was this community of people
所以有这个人社区
who've been doing these things,
谁在做这些事情，
building the software, advocating based on it.
构建该软件，根据它提倡。
this very popular movement called cypherpunks.
这个非常受欢迎的运动称为Cypherpunks。
Here on this picture, looking kind of scared with the mask,
在这张照片上，看上去有点害怕面具，
but we can unmask them.
但是我们可以揭露它们。
The cypherpunks were many different people
cypherpunks有很多不同的人
from different academia, from business,
来自不同学术界，商业，
computer scientists, programmers,
计算机科学家，程序员，
or just researchers who've been building these tools.
或者只是构建这些工具的研究人员。
they started a cypherpunk mailing list which is a famous place where many of these tools
他们开始了一个Cypherpunk邮件列表，这是一个著名的地方，其中许多工具
were announced like ssh was announced there i believe bitcoin was announced there
宣布了SSH宣布，我相信比特币已在那里宣布
on the right here uh on the on the very right is um uh gilmore um who've been
在右边的右边是右边的嗯，嗯，吉尔莫尔
who've been uh the founder of electronic frontier foundation uh eff very important organization until
谁一直是电子边界基金会的创始人UH EFF非常重要的组织，直到
until today. In the middle, Eric Hughes, the author of the Cypherpunk Manifesto, he actually
直到今天。在中间，Cypherpunk宣言的作者埃里克·休斯（Eric Hughes）实际上
wrote down these principles that the cypherpunks believed in, in a manifesto which
写下了Cypherpunks相信的这些原则，在一份宣言中
excerpt of it is here on the slide, where he talks about that part that we build some distributed,
它的摘录在幻灯片上，他在那里谈论我们构建一些分布式的那部分，
open free software, which cannot be, which can't be, um, somehow
打开免费软件，这是不可能的，嗯，以某种方式
forbidden, forgotten, because it's really, uh, uh, uh, uh,
禁止，被遗忘，因为它确实是，嗯，呃，呃，呃，
because it's free and it's, it's, uh, just form of a form of a
因为它是免费的，而且是，它是，呃，只是一种形式的形式
speech form of, uh, um, uh, explanation of mathematics, for
语音形式，嗯，嗯，呃，数学解释，用于
example, uh, uh, all the famously, they produced, uh,
例如，嗯，呃，所有著名的人，他们生产了，呃，
t-shirts with the cryptography code on it. So like, you know,
带有加密代码的T恤。所以，你知道，
I have illegal words on my t-shirt. This is illegal mathematical notation here.
我的T恤上有非法的话。这是这里非法的数学符号。
So yeah, I really recommend getting inspired by the Cypherpunk Manifesto.
是的，我真的建议您受到Cypherpunk宣言的启发。
On the left here is Timothy C. May who
左边是蒂莫西·C·梅
was, I think, chief scientist at Intel. He has some interesting inventions there, but in this
我认为是英特尔的首席科学家。他在那里有一些有趣的发明，但是
context, he, as one of the founders of the Cypherpunk Male English, Cypherpunk movement,
上下文，他是Cypherpunk男性英语的创始人之一，Cypherpunk运动，
he um he takes this idea a bit further he creates manifesto of cryptanarchy where he uh talks about
他嗯，他将这个想法进一步提出了他创造的Cryptanarchy宣言，他在谈论
uh about these tools not just as like we are able to create them and and and have privacy and
嗯，这些工具不仅像我们能够创建它们并拥有隐私和
protect ourselves but we can actually create a digital realm this digital world where we can
保护自己，但我们实际上可以创建一个数字领域，在这个数字世界中我们可以
can uh be completely free protected we can uh have uh digital money anonymous uh
可以完全免费保护，我们可以拥有uh数字货币匿名
anonymous credentials uh our own reputation uh uh systems our own markets uh Etc so like uh these
匿名凭证呃，我们自己的声誉呃，呃，我们自己的市场等等，所以像这些
were the people already envisioning uh digital currencies based on cryptography uh in in well
是否已经设想了基于密码学的UH数字货币uh in Well
early 90s and in late 80s, we had this idea already.
90年代初和80年代末，我们已经有了这个想法。
David Chow famously created a DigiCache, one of the cypherpunks as well.
大卫·乔（David Chow）著名地创造了Digicache，这也是Cypherpunk之一。
So we see these attempts and we see
因此，我们看到了这些尝试，我们看到了
these ideas pointing to some
这些想法指的是
uncensorable free digital platforms.
无可讯息的免费数字平台。
Yeah, and with all of this,
是的，所有这一切，
the question that arises, like, how Ethereum fits
以太坊如何适应的问题
in all of this uh this is of course like my somewhat subjective point of view and i don't
在所有这一切中，这当然就像我的某种主观的观点一样
want to i want to influence your opinion and i want to ask you guys like uh i kind of described
想我想影响你的意见，我想问你们像嗯，我有点描述
in this view on history how i see ethereum where i see it's coming from and what are its values and
在有关历史的观点中
uh in the last part kind of what it is but i want to ask you what do you think the ethereum is can
嗯，这是什么是什么，但我想问你你认为以太坊是什么
you describe ethereum in one word or one sentence write it to the discord chat i'm going to check it
您用一个单词或一句话描述以太坊，将其写入Discord Chat，我要检查它
uh in the in the thread
嗯，在线程中
world computer cool cool
世界电脑酷酷
Yeah, John Gilmore, a superlative employee. Yeah, yeah. Good. That's his credits.
是的，最高级员工约翰·吉尔莫尔（John Gilmore）。是啊是啊。好的。那是他的荣誉。
Non-stoppable, lovely computer. Oh, I love that. Yeah, we have many different opinions.
不稳定，可爱的计算机。哦，我喜欢那个。是的，我们有许多不同的意见。
Decentralized web, decentralized computer, trustless trust, world computer as well, and trustlessness.
分散的网络，分散计算机，无信任的信任，世界计算机以及无信任性。
State machine. Oh, I love that. Cool, cool.
状态机。哦，我喜欢那个。酷，很酷。
Well, we have many different opinions, but I got to say, all of you are correct, of course.
好吧，我们有许多不同的意见，但是我必须说，你们所有人当然都是正确的。
I think there is no single way
我认为没有单一的方式
we could define Ethereum
我们可以定义以太坊
because everybody
因为每个人
sees a different part of it
看到其中的另一部分
oh new internet it's also a cool one
哦，新互联网也很酷
I believe all of this is right
我相信所有这些都是正确的
I believe that
我相信
Ethereum is this digital
以太坊是这个数字
realm that
领域
anybody can find their place
任何人都可以找到他们的位置
in anybody can
任何人都可以
see it from different
从不同的
perspective and
观点和
you know depends on what's your
你知道取决于你的
motivation where you're coming from what you're interested in what you're working on you have
您来自您对工作的事物感兴趣的动力
a certain tunnel vision of like what the ethereum is for you how do you envision it so this uh this
某种隧道的愿景，就像以太坊对您所要设想的是什么，所以这个
little elephant here is what we are talking about and uh in this talk of course i need to focus on
这是我们在谈论的小象，当然我需要关注的是
the whole elephant on the on the technical part of the protocol itself um i uh need to talk more
协议本身的技术部分上的整个大象嗯，我需要谈论更多
about like hands-on what is it's ethereum um and uh yeah uh so because what we have all in
就像动手一样，是什么是以太坊，嗯，是的
common even if we have like different views on it uh we want to achieve these goals we want to
即使我们对此有不同的看法，我们想实现我们想要的这些目标
achieve these visions and that means that we need to uh use and improve ethereum to
实现这些愿景，这意味着我们需要使用UH并改善以太坊
uh to be able to get there and to answer like what is ethereum uh yeah in there there are many simple
嗯，能够到达那里并回答什么是以太坊，呃，那里有很多简单
terms uh another description of what is ethereum of course you could point people to white paper
术语吧，呃，当然可以指出人们的另一个以太坊的描述
if somebody asks what it here it's a description of what the theorem is uh from 10 years ago now
如果有人问这是什么描述，即10年前的定理是什么
uh and here in uh italic revealing it on bitcoin miami lineup for that conference changed quite a
嗯，在uh Italic上，在迈阿密比特币阵容上揭示了这次会议的变化很大。
a lot. Yeah, so it's one way.
很多。是的，这是一种方式。
The white paper is more of a general high level
白皮书更像是一般的高水平
description. It's more of an idea of how this
描述。这更多的是如何这样做
network should work.
网络应该起作用。
But we can take it further to yellow paper, which
但是我们可以将其进一步发展到黄纸
is the actual formal specification of
是实际的正式规范
Ethereum. It's written by Gavin Wood, one of the
以太坊。它是由加文·伍德（Gavin Wood）撰写的
founders of Ethereum, also creator of the original C++ implementation, who actually
以太坊的创始人，也是原始C ++实施的创建者，实际上
sit down to write down how it's supposed to work, not just in theory, but practically
坐下来写下它应该如何工作，不仅在理论上，而且实际上是
using mathematics, using formal expressions, how it's how Ethereum is supposed to be
使用数学，使用正式表达式，以太坊应该如何成为
implemented according to the specification. So that's one way, and you see here that it's
根据规范实施。所以这是一种方式，您在这里看到它是
it's Berlin version the current version is Paris so it's already uh out of date but uh it's always
这是柏林版本当前版本是巴黎，所以它已经过时了，但是它总是
because ethereum is changing this is just like the original it was just like some original vision
因为以太坊正在改变这种情况，就像原始的一样，就像一些原始愿景
uh but it's not the only way where only place where it's pretty much specified it's not just
呃，但这不是唯一只有大量指定的位置的唯一方法不仅仅是
Vitalik or Gavin or Rubin or these founders who define what ethereum is but it's the community so
Vitalik，Gavin或Rubin或这些定义以太坊的创始人，但是社区，所以
using this process of ethereum Improvement proposals anybody can propose a change to
使用以太坊改进的过程，任何人都可以提出更改
Ethereum improvement or or um uh change they believe is uh is um important to it um the
以太坊的改进或或或um uh uh改变他们认为是嗯，对此很重要
EAP process is inspired by the bib process from Bitcoin Improvement proposals started by Amir
EAP过程的灵感来自Amir发起的比特币改进建议的围嘴过程
Taki uh which is inspired by the similar processing Python and it's generally a community way of uh
受类似处理Python的启发的Taki UH，这通常是社区的一种UH的方式
working on this big distributed project.
从事这个大型分布式项目。
But having yellow paper plus EIPs and you are supposed to implement something based
但是拥有黄纸加EIP，您应该实施基于的东西
on it, it's kind of a mess, right?
在上面，这有点混乱，对吗？
Like all of these different documents.
像所有这些不同的文档一样。
So we actually have a proper specification in these two repositories.
因此，我们实际上在这两个存储库中有适当的规范。
That's the execution specs and consensus specs.
这就是执行规格和共识规格。
with all the APIs here, that's what really defines all of the Ethereum and the way it's
在这里所有的API，这就是真正定义所有以太坊的原因
supposed to work.
应该工作。
It's written in Python, and for some people, people like me, it's hard for me to read the
它是用python写的，对于某些人，像我这样的人，我很难阅读
mathematical rotations in yellow paper, and in Python it actually is even more readable.
黄纸和python中的数学旋转实际上更可读。
And of course you can generate tests based on this, you can test your implementation
当然，您可以基于此生成测试，您可以测试您的实现
against the specification so it's a very practical and very very useful way that we specify the
反对规格，因此我们指定的是一种非常实用且非常有用的方法
theorem here and of course if you are not programmer or if you just want to learn about
当然，如果您不是程序员，或者您只想了解
the way it works it's pretty heavy to read the code i would recommend reading annotated
它的工作方式很重，可以阅读我建议阅读注释的代码
specification which comes with explanation uh how it works why it works this way
说明的规范呃，它是如何工作的，为什么它是这样工作的
way, and it gives you a context.
方式，它为您提供了一个上下文。
So for example, the one from Ben Eddington here, the E2 book.
因此，例如，Ben Eddington的一本书，E2书。
So there are versions of this specification, different versions of Ethereum.
因此，有此规范的版本，以太坊的不同版本。
We also call it hard forks, the Ethereum upgrades, which have been happening well now for 10
我们还称其为Hard Forks，即以太坊升级，现在已经发生了10个
years and um starting with the frontier homestead many years ago uh uh now um you can you can see
多年前从边境宅基地开始的年和UM，嗯，嗯，您可以看到
all the history all of the upgrades in uh in the ethereum org uh where you see what eips what
所有历史记录在以太坊中的UH中的所有升级
upgrades have been coupled in each of these each of these upgrades um however um even though ethereum
这些升级已在这些升级中的每一个中都耦合在一起，但是即使以太坊
changes a lot is developed uh heavily over these well 10 years now it's it's always adheres to
在十年井中，大量发展了很多变化，这总是遵守
certain principles there are basic tenets that uh ethereum design must follow it was outlined
某些原则有uh以太坊设计必须遵循的基本原则。
in this now non-existing website uh archived there it's really nice explained there i recommend
在这个现在不存在的网站上，uh存档了，我建议在这里解释很不错
diving into that uh but the point is that these developers need to have certain values uh need to
潜入那个UH，但要点是这些开发人员需要具有某些值
need to follow some rules, some design decisions,
需要遵守某些规则，一些设计决策，
and we cannot take trade-offs which would disprove this.
而且我们不能取舍这会反驳这一点。
So, yeah, simplicity, universality, modularity,
所以，是的，简单，普遍性，模块化，
non-discrimination, agility, these are the basic principles
非歧视，敏捷性，这些是基本原理
in a way that Ethereum needs to be as simple as possible
以以太坊需要尽可能简单的方式
in a way that needs to be possible to somewhat easily implemented it needs to be you know
在某种需要轻松实施的方式中，您需要知道
re-implementable if you compare it to like i don't know linux kernel like i cannot imagine
如果您将其比较，我不知道Linux内核，就像我无法想象的那样，可以重新实现
somebody just like writing another version of that um universality so uh ethereum also like
有人喜欢写另一个版本的UM普遍性，所以以太坊也喜欢
the generalization and no features in the later part, the universality and
在后面的普遍性和普遍性和
non-generalization means that Ethereum is not discriminating, it's not
非一般化意味着以太坊没有歧视，不是
biased towards certain features. Ethereum is not supposed to do a single thing but rather be a
偏向某些功能。以太坊不应该做一件事情，而是要成为
generalized platform for whatever people want to use. This means that the core protocol does not,
对于人们想使用的任何人的广义平台。这意味着核心协议没有，
it cannot include features which would define some user behavior or something more high-level.
它不能包含可以定义某些用户行为或更高级别的功能。
For example, there cannot be token standard implemented in the core protocol.
例如，核心协议中无法实现令牌标准。
With the ERCs, people create it on top of Ethereum, but it's not within the protocol
使用ERC，人们在以太坊之上创建它，但不在协议中
itself.
本身。
The modularity I already talked about, and you will see it as I show you the protocol later.
我已经谈论过的模块化，当我以后向您展示协议时，您会看到它。
But what we follow here in Ethereum is that also with the encapsulated complexity mentioned here,
但是，我们在以太坊中所关注的是，此处提到的封装复杂性也是如此
we encapsulate different parts of Ethereum, different parts of the network,
我们封装以太坊的不同部分，网络的不同部分，
and they talk to each other within some relatively simple API.
他们在一些相对简单的API中互相交谈。
So we are able to debug it.
因此，我们可以调试它。
we are able to have more security if only one of these parts fail.
如果只有其中一个失败，我们就能拥有更多的安全性。
And yeah, one thing I want to elaborate is the non-risk version
是的，我想阐述的一件事是非风险版本
that as the Ethereum changes,
随着以太坊的变化，
the changes are conditioned by what benefit they bring.
这些变化取决于它们带来的好处。
So the developers are willing to take certain risk for certain benefit, right?
因此，开发商愿意以某些利益冒险，对吗？
if there is a small change which bring us a huge benefits it's definitely worth doing it
如果有很小的变化给我们带来巨大的好处，那么绝对值得这样做
so that's uh it is a principle and I'm sorry guys it's too early for me um yeah now I want to ask
所以这是一个原则，对不起，我现在想问我还为时过早
you when I talked about the different modules different parts of it here I've always mentioned
当我谈论不同部分的不同部分时，我一直在这里提到
like parts of the protocol and whatnot what would you consider is the heart of ethereum the the the
就像协议的各个部分一样，您认为什么是以太坊的心脏
important part we should start from let's build it here in together and
重要的部分，我们应该从让我们一起在这里构建它，然后
let's let's see what would you consider is the is the brain the heart of it
让我们看看您会认为是大脑的心脏
clearly yeah right right right into the group okay it's the EVM consensus people
显然是的，就直接进入小组，好吧，这是EVM共识人
Oh, that's nice.
哦，很好。
So what else?
那还有什么呢？
Feel free to write.
随意写。
Philosophy.
哲学。
Okay, I'm talking more about it.
好吧，我在谈论更多。
It's really nice to see the people or philosophy.
看到人或哲学真是太好了。
I mean, technically, the modular part.
从技术上讲，我的意思是模块化部分。
Okay, the data structures.
好的，数据结构。
Yeah, now you don't see anything because I'm waiting for you to reveal it.
是的，现在您什么都看不到，因为我正在等待您透露它。
The peer-to-peer network.
点对点网络。
Okay.
好的。
Miracle tree.
奇迹树。
Okay, guys.
好吧，伙计们。
uh again i believe that i believe that you are right uh i believe that all of you are rights
嗯，我相信我相信你是对的，我相信你们所有人都是权利
because these are all important part of ethereum uh i wanted to start from um from um from somewhere
因为这些都是以太坊的重要组成部分，所以我想从UM开始
so when i ask about the heart of ethereum i wanted to start with evm uh that's like uh often often
因此，当我询问以太坊的心脏时，我想从经常像EVM开始
mentioned important part of ethereum and it's it's pretty much uh all of the core um very
提到以太坊的重要部分，这几乎是所有的核心
it's interior specific features so what is cvm it's well it's a basically a virtualized cpu
它是内部特定功能，所以什么是CVM，这是一个基本上是虚拟化的CPU
uh now if you are using your computer here you either have x86 or arm uh based cpu with like
呃，如果您在这里使用计算机，则您的X86或基于ARM UH的CPU
instruction set specific to the architecture it it's a hardware which implements some instruction
指令集特定于体系结构，这是一个硬件，可实现某些指令
sets some basic assembly some basic instructions which are able to do logic arithmetic and work
设置一些基本的组件，一些能够执行逻辑算术并起作用的基本说明
with data to uh to well do anything like your computer can do anything or everything um uh to
使用数据到uh做得很好，例如计算机可以做任何事情或所有事情
be a general purpose machine so that's it's on the hardware level but in in software in in programming
成为通用机器，因此它在硬件级别，但在编程中的软件中
in computer science what we often do is virtualize these instruction sets uh we create virtual
在计算机科学中，我们经常做的是虚拟化这些指令集，呃，我们创建虚拟
machines for example if you're a developer again maybe you worked with uh jvm the java virtual
例如，如果您再次是开发人员，也许您使用JVM Java虚拟
machine uh these machines are created so that if you write you know if you write a certain code it
这些机器是创建这些机器的机器
might do it might behave somewhat differently on different machines from different manufacturers
可能会在不同制造商的不同机器上的行为可能有所不同
which can understand some instructions slightly differently let's say uh famously said like it
可以理解某些说明略有不同
it works on my machine.
它在我的机器上起作用。
So now if you want to replicate this experience,
所以现在，如果您想复制这种经验，
it works on my machine,
它在我的机器上工作，
I create a virtual environment,
我创建一个虚拟环境，
which is always the same on every machine,
在每台机器上总是相同的
because if I execute something
因为如果我执行某件事
in this virtual environment,
在这个虚拟环境中，
it will always end up in the same result.
它总是会以相同的结果结束。
That's what EVM is.
这就是EVM。
It's a virtual machine,
这是一台虚拟机，
which has its own instruction set
有自己的指令集
with like 30-ish something of codes.
有30个代码。
Um, uh, and these, these can, these are Turing complete, they can do anything.
嗯，嗯，这些，这些都可以完成，它们可以做任何事情。
Um, the, uh, the, the, the, the EVM is, is the actual execution engine, the environment where, uh, the Ethereum programs are, are, are run.
um，uh，，，，，，，，evm是实际的执行引擎，是运行以太坊程序的环境。
And now if all of the computers, every computer running Ethereum has the same virtual machine or the same implementation, but it's implemented through the same specification can be implemented now in different languages and different ways.
现在，如果所有计算机，每个运行以太坊的计算机都具有相同的虚拟机或相同的实现，但是现在可以通过相同规范实现，现在可以以不同的语言和不同的方式实现。
And if it's still follow the specification, the result of the execution, the result of the run of the program within this virtual machine will always be the same.
如果仍然遵循规范，则执行的结果，该虚拟机中程序运行的结果将始终相同。
It means that all of these Ethereum clients can agree on something.
这意味着所有这些以太坊客户都可以就某事达成共识。
it. I would also mention here the sandwich complexity that I have in previous slide.
它。我还会在这里提到我先前幻灯片中的三明治复杂性。
That's how it works. So you might probably have heard about Solidity or Viper or some
那就是它的工作方式。因此，您可能听说过坚固或毒蛇或一些
other of these high-level languages, which are readable and auditable. And then we have
这些高级语言中的其他，这些语言是可读和可审计的。然后我们有
very complex compiler, which is a huge part and it's a beast. Very complex. And on the
非常复杂的编译器，这是一个很大的部分，它是野兽。非常复杂。在
bottom, we have the EVM bytecode, the instructions for this virtual machine, which again, there is
底部，我们有EVM字节码，该虚拟机的指令，又有
not so many of them, and it's somehow readable, somehow formally verifiable, what the actual
它们不是很多，它是可以阅读的，以某种方式正式可验证，实际的
virtual machine does. So when we have like these two non-complex pieces, with the complexity in
虚拟机确实。因此，当我们喜欢这两个非复合件时，
the middle, it creates a complexity sandwich, with the EVM on the bottom. But for EVM to work,
中间，它会产生一个复杂的三明治，而evm在底部。但是为了使EVM工作，
it needs some data it needs to input and output some data so for that we have um uh the state um
它需要一些数据来输入和输出一些数据，因此我们拥有状态UM
so the data in ethereum uh the data structure database which holds all of the uh all of the
因此，以太坊中的数据uh数据结构数据库，该数据库包含所有uh
aggressors its balances its current state uh the current state of the network of all of the
侵略者平衡其当前状态UH所有网络的当前状态
contracts all of the uh of all um the the the code and the data of all of the contracts right
合同所有um the Code和所有合同的数据
uh this is what we call the state i know many of you are anarchists you don't like state in ethereum
嗯，这就是我们所说的状态，我知道你们中的许多人是您不喜欢以太坊州的无政府主义者
we have state because ethereum is a state machine uh state machine is a principle from uh from a
我们之所以州，是因为以太坊是状态机UH状态机是UH的原理
computer science where we have again a machine which can result in different states and different
计算机科学，我们再次拥有一台可以导致不同状态和不同状态的机器
inputs um so so evm processes uh outputs some data updates the state uh creates we call it
输入嗯，所以evm处理uh输出一些数据更新状态UH创建我们称之为
state transition based on some input which is transactions so transactions uh are these
国家过渡基于某些输入，即交易，所以交易是
instructions on how the state transition is supposed to happen and if it's correct if it
有关国家过渡如何发生的说明以及如果是正确的话
if it works within the rules of the evm the network it uh creates a successful state
如果它在EVM规则中起作用，则它会创建成功的状态
transition we update the state of ethereum um if you are familiar with bitcoin design if you
过渡，如果您熟悉比特币设计，我们会更新以太坊的状态
uh or similar utxo based uh cryptocurrencies this is where the major difference is ethereum has a
UH或类似的基于UTXO的UH加密货币这是主要区别是以太坊的地方
single global state basically one database which has the current state the current value of
单个全球状态基本上是一个具有当前状态的当前值的数据库
everything uh in bitcoin or other currencies we have like utxos we have uh uh just unspended
所有的比特币或其他货币的uh，我们拥有的UTXOS，我们有UH uh
outputs of each transaction and uh not a single single uh single state so so this is this is uh
每个事务的输出，uh不是一个单个UH单个状态，所以这就是uh
what is one of the design decisions in ethereum one way it works this state is a big merkle tree
以太坊中的设计决定之一是什么方式，它是一个大的默克尔树
america patricia tree and uh the transactions are um are stored in a different tree but update this
美国帕特里夏树和嗯，交易已存储在另一棵树中，但更新此
thing uh they are uh the transactions of course come from mempool which is um the pool of all
嗯，他们是嗯，交易当然来自Mempool，这是所有人的库
the transactions coming to the network and those are uh those are uh gossiped over peer-to-peer
交易来到网络，那是uh，那些是在点对点上闲聊的
network um so the peer-to-peer is um the communication interface with other clients
网络UM，因此点对点是与其他客户的通信接口
uh with other nodes in the network which can broadcast transactions so your
嗯，网络中的其他节点可以广播交易，所以您
uh uh your transactions uh go through um this particular network and each client which receives
呃，您的交易嗯
it verifies whether it's correct and and then if it's correct uh again broadcast it to all of
它验证它是否正确，然后是否正确地将其广播给所有
these peers so um even if the network is big and decentralized that is uh the transaction
即使网络大且分散，这些同行也是如此，这是交易
spreads to all of the network and uh this all of this much more but let's say this uh
传播到所有网络，并将所有这一切都付诸实践，但可以说
is the execution layer this would be called the execution part of ethereum um if you are using
是执行层，如果您使用的话，这将称为以太坊的执行部分
some uh ethereum wallet or if you are using some dap some uh you know distal application um you are
某些uh以太坊钱包，或者如果您在使用一些DAP，您知道远端应用程序UM
talking to this to the execution layer of ethereum using some standardized uh api it's a rpc json rpc
使用一些标准化的UH API与以太坊的执行层交谈，这是RPC JSON RPC
api uh which can read the current data if you want to know you know how much eat is on this account
如果您想知道您知道在此帐户上有多少饮食，可以读取当前数据的API UH
you need to read the state so you read the data from the execution layer or if you want to write
您需要阅读状态，以便从执行层读取数据或是否要编写
if you want to send a transaction your wallet signs it and then sends it to this client to
如果要发送交易，您的钱包标志将其发送给该客户端
broadcast it to the network over the uh the client receives it verifies it and sends it to the peer
将其广播到网络上的uh uh接收到它验证它并将其发送给对等
to peer layer so this is the execution part um now another api that uh the client implements
要等层，所以这是执行部分UM现在的另一个api
it's engine api uh which talks to uh the consensus part of it so uh how does this execution know what
这是引擎API UH，它与uh的共识部分交谈，因此该执行如何知道什么
is correct what is the head of the chain what all of the other uh all of the other nodes agree on
正确的是链的头是什么，其他所有节点都同意
uh in the i put a link to the uh bft the uh presenting fault tolerance problem
嗯，我在uh bft上链接了UH呈现的容错问题
in um in the in the docs and this is where it comes like uh we need to agree on what is the
在文档中的um中，这就是像嗯，我们需要就什么是什么
current state of the whole equilibrium not just as i see this one single piece of the network
整个平衡的当前状态不仅是我看到的这一部分网络
and uh this is uh dictated to the execution client or this execution layer by a fork choice
嗯，这是由叉子选择向执行客户端或该执行层指示的
which is of course managed by the consensus algorithm of Ethereum, the LMD Ghost, or the
当然，这是由以太坊，LMD幽灵或
latest message-driven, greediest, heaviest observed sub-tree, which is very jargon-heavy
最新的消息驱动，最贪婪，最重的观察到的子树，非常术语
way to explain this fork-trace rule and this consensus mechanism, which based on number
解释这一叉形规则和这种共识机制的方法，该机制基于数字
of uh the most number of other stations the fork or the the tree chain with the with the most
UH最多的其他站点是叉子或树链的数量最多
boats the most stations is the one which is considered canonical and um uh then it's dictated
船最多的电台是被认为是规范和嗯，嗯
by fork choice to the to the client uh and this together with its own peer-to-peer network and
通过将叉子选择到客户端，uh，以及它自己的点对点网络以及
some other parts with the current hard work we have the blobs with the random which dictates
其他一些具有当前努力工作的部分，我们有随机的斑点
the randomness uh all of this this is the consensus layer so uh ethereum right now is these two
所有这些都是随机性，这是共识层，所以以太坊现在是这两个
layers connected to each other and um over the engine api and it's uh uh and uh yeah and the
彼此连接的图层，并在发动机API上连接，呃，是的，是的
consensus also has its own api you can also communicate with this client again to learn
共识也有其自己的API，您也可以再次与该客户进行交流以学习
now about state but not the theorem itself not about like accounts and transactions but about
现在关于状态，而不是定理本身，而不是喜欢帐户和交易，而是关于
the consensus state how many validators are there how many uh what validators do what are the
共识指出有多少验证者有多少uh uh验证器做什么是什么
stations what is the finalized uh head of the chain etc we we ask uh from the beacon api of
电台是什么是链条的最终uh头等，我们从信标API中问UH
the consensus player uh if you are running a validator if you are participating in the consensus
共识播放器uh如果您正在进行验证器（如果您参与共识）
uh your beacon node or this this consensus layer verifies uh the latest block sends it to the
呃，您的信标节点或此共识层验证uh最新块将其发送到
execution layer to verify uh uh the integrity of the block and then uh if it's considered valid
执行层以验证uh uh块的完整性，然后如果被认为有效，则uh
the validator uses its keys to to sign an attestation okay i believe that this network
验证者使用其密钥签署证明，我相信这个网络
uh this this uh block is correct i attest to it and sends this data the signature uh to the
嗯，这个uh块是正确的，我证明了它，并将此数据发送给签名uh
consensus layer which where it's broadcasted over its own peer-to-peer network so the consensus
共识层是通过其自己的点对点网络广播的，以便共识
has its own peer-to-peer it's a different from from execution layer this so this whole thing
有自己的点对点，与执行层不同，所以这整个事情
is like simplified overview of different parts of the protocol again from what i said before
就像我之前所说的简化了协议不同部分的简化概述
you can really like each of these boxes are huge rabbit holes you can dive into each of these and
您真的可以喜欢这些盒子中的每个盒子都是巨大的兔子孔
and become an expert of uh on uh literally every single box here um and to make it a bit more
并成为UH上UH的专家
high level it will abstract so these are implemented in clients in the execution engine
高水平将抽象化，因此这些是在执行引擎中的客户端中实现的
the execution client or the execution layer client and the beacon node or the consensus client and
执行客户端或执行层客户端和信标节点或共识客户端以及
the process layer client different words for those uh each of those have their own peer-to-peer
过程层客户端的不同单词为每个人都有自己的点对点
network on the right side the execution clients are only talking to the execution clients and
右侧的网络执行客户端仅与执行客户端进行对话
the bq nodes are only looking for bk notes they are they have they have their own communication
BQ节点只是在寻找bk注释，他们有自己的交流
protocols it's dev peer-to-peer for the execution and a little peer-to-peer for the for the beacon
协议是执行的开发点对点，而对信标的对等点对点
and they have their own APIs which provide different different data and they need to be
他们有自己的API提供不同的数据，需要成为
connected over the engine API so yeah this is this is this is like high-level overview of
连接在引擎API上，是的，这就是这就像这样的高级概述
of uh what constitutes an ethereum node or ethereum client these two parts connected
什么构成以太坊节点或以太坊客户端的uh
uh but of course this is somewhat new uh uh this is uh this is something that that happened after
嗯，但是当然这有点新的嗯，这是嗯，这是在此之后发生的事情
the merge um so to show you the the peer-to-peer network uh this is how ethereum looks like right
合并，向您展示点对点网络嗯，这就是以太坊的样子
just to give it's again something basic but just to give you an idea of on the left what is
只是给它再次是基本的东西，但只是为了让您了解左边
centralized if you're watching the stream right now or if you're watching the recording your
集中化如果您现在正在观看流，或者您正在观看录音
computers or are uh connecting to a single server which is sending data to all of you guys um but
计算机或UH连接到单个服务器，该服务器正在向所有人发送数据，但是
interior it's similar to more something on the right uh maybe in the chart everybody's connected
内饰类似于右边的更多内容，呃，在图表中，每个人都连接
with everybody which is not really true uh you are connected to some nodes those are connected
每个人都不是真正真实的嗯，您与某些节点连接在一起
to some etc you can be connected to everyone but uh each node can be connected to tens or hundreds
对于某些等，您可以连接到每个人，但是每个节点可以连接到数十个或数百个
of different peers uh we call them peers because they are on the same level this like and this
在不同的同龄人中，我们称他们为同龄人，因为他们在相同的层面上，这样
ethereum network doesn't have any any master uh no masters no single points of failures as we said
以太坊网络没有任何主人没有任何大师，没有单一的失败点
so uh it has uh it has all all nodes on the on the same level everybody's peer and uh can talk
所以呃，它有嗯，它在同一级别上都有所有的节点，每个人的同伴都可以说话
to each other and can connect so so your so the client discovers the nodes around him connects
彼此之间可以连接，因此您的客户会发现他周围的节点连接
to them and exchanges the gossip data over the particular layer and this way so uh yeah and to
向他们和通过特定层交换八卦数据，这样，是的
show you how the block looks like with uh this consensus execution client connected uh this wasn't
向您展示该块的外观如何使用此共识执行客户端连接uh这不是
the true before the merge on the left here you see the old ethereum before the merge the proof
在左边合并之前的真实您会在合并证明之前看到旧以太坊
of work ethereum uh where the beacon chain and the ethereum were basically separate things they were
信标链和以太坊的职业以太坊基本上是分开的
separate networks the beacon chain was uh looking into the ethereum for the deposit contract for the
单独的网络信标连锁店正在研究以太坊的存款合同
validated data there but uh the ethereum itself didn't learn didn't use uh the big engine in any
经过验证的数据，但是以太坊本身没有学会任何人都没有使用任何大引擎
way in the middle this is the moment of the merge where the uh the the block from the the execution
中间的方式是合并的时刻
layer becomes part of the block of the beacon chain so in the execution layer we have the uh
图层成为信标链块的一部分，因此在执行层中我们有UH
we have the transaction data you see all the transactions from zero to n and they're they're
我们有交易数据，您会看到从零到n的所有交易，它们是他们
in the merkle tree and their root is in the in the in the header um and the hash of this header is
在默克尔树上，它们的根部位于标题UM中，该标题的哈希是
the hash of the whole block, right? And the beacon chain is now, you see it holds all the
整个块的哈希，对吗？信标连锁店现在，您会看到它拥有所有的
attestations, attestation zero to n, so the signatures which are confirming that this
证明，证明为零至n，因此确认这一点的签名
execution layer block, this transaction data, this block was verified, then this deposits and exits
执行层块，此事务数据，该块已验证，然后存放并退出
from the from the validators um and yeah this is this is how the on the right uh yeah the the the
来自验证者嗯，是的，这就是正确的嗯，是的
the uh arrows are pointed to the left it might now i realize it might look a bit uh uh confusing but
UH箭头指向左侧，现在我意识到它看起来有点混乱，但是
it's of course this is the blockchain right the in the blockchain we hash the previous we include
当然，这是一个区块链，就在我们哈希中的区块链中，我们包括
the hash of the previous block so this block references the previous one uh so on the right
上一个块的哈希，因此此块引用了上一个uh uh so y so
here you see how the how the blocks look like today with the execution data with transaction
在这里，您可以通过交易的执行数据看到今天的块的样子
data within the within the beacon chain and now yeah so this this this little thing this beacon
信标链内的数据，现在是的，所以这是这个小问题
and execution node like all of these ports implemented in these clients are actually
像这些客户端中实现的所有这些端口一样，执行节点实际上是
written in some languages as actual programs that you can run right that's the whole point so this
用某些语言作为实际程序编写，您可以直接运行，这是全部的重点，所以
is where it comes together this is how you use it theory so if you want to become an ethereum user
是汇聚在一起的地方，这是您使用理论的方式，因此，如果您想成为以太坊用户
which means use ethereum privately trustlessly securely you run some of these clients which
这意味着您可以私下私人信任地使用以太坊，您经营其中一些客户
verify the the data in the network and let you interact with it let you connect to um
验证网络中的数据并让您与之互动，让您连接到UM
to the actual ethereum network to send transactions to read its data without entering parties this is
到实际以太坊网络发送交易以读取其数据而不进入各方的数据是
This is actually Ethereum.
这实际上是以太坊。
So the implementation of the execution layer of what was the bottom part in my chart
因此，我图表中最底部的执行层的执行层的实现
is GoEthereum in Go, never mind in .NET C Sharp,
在Go中是Goethereum，没关系。
Bessu in Java,
Bessu在Java，
Ergon in Go was originally stored as a turbo-gat,
埃尔贡（Ergon）最初被存储为涡轮螺旋体，
as a fork of GoEthereum,
作为Goethereum的叉子，
but later developed its very unique architecture,
但是后来开发了非常独特的建筑，
but still keeps some part of the Go code base,
但是仍然保留了GO代码基础的一部分，
or it's still in Go,
或者它仍在
while a red uh is written in rust and it's basically using the arrogant architecture silkworm
红色UH用生锈写，基本上是使用自大的建筑蚕
is uh uh rest it's an alpha red like these four on the top are production ready those are running
呃，吧，嗯，这是一个α红色，就像顶部的四个已经准备好了
the network the network consists of instances of the computers running the software in the first
网络网络由第一个计算机的实例组成
row in the second row the red is uh in alpha there are some people who are running it but it's like
第二行中的行红色是uh在alpha中有些人正在运行它，但就像
you know not recommended for production use silkworm is still in development it's also
您知道不建议用于生产蚕的生产仍在开发中
implementation of the array architecture in more modular way and then there is ethereum js which
以更模块化的方式实现数组体系结构，然后有以太坊JS
is in javascript typescript and uh this one is more of an experimental client for um used for
是在JavaScript打字条中，嗯，这更多是用于UM的实验客户端
testing used used for verifying the specs etc and then on the consensus layer side the upper part
用于验证规格等的测试，然后在共识层侧面的上部
which drives the uh the the consensus the validators uh these are all production or
驱动着验证者的共识，这些都是生产的或
declines which are again running the network um prism and go lighthouse and rust teco in java from
从java中的灯塔和灯塔和Rust Teco的降低
uh nimbus and neiman roadster in typescript uh there are other clients which are not
UH Nimbus和Neiman Roadster在打字稿中，还有其他客户
productionary which are in development and there is one proprietary client
生产正在开发，有一个专有客户
brain in the data convention and there is a client in elixir developed by lambda class which is also
数据公约中的大脑，在Lambda类开发的Elixir中有一个客户，也是
like in production already but uh there are others in development as well but these are those that
就像在生产中一样
are there are ready you can actually go to their repositories learn about them because as i said
是否准备好了，您实际上可以去他们的存储库了解了有关它们的知识，因为正如我所说
before all this is free and open source so you can actually look into the client code
在所有这些都是免费的和开源之前，因此您实际上可以查看客户端代码
bases to make sure that you know they follow the specs you can contribute there
基础以确保您知道他们遵循可以在那里贡献的规格
and to ensure the security stability of the network uh this all of these clients need to
并确保网络的安全稳定性，这些客户需要
be tested need to be heavily tested because well the network is out there running like huge amounts
进行测试需要进行大量测试，因为网络在那里运行良好
of money and people's funds and whatnot so we cannot just you know uh take it recklessly and
金钱和人民的资金等等，所以我们不能只知道你鲁ck和
uh we heavily test these clients the client teams the developers and other test
嗯，我们大量测试这些客户的客户团队开发人员和其他测试
teams which are dedicated just to testing and security are uh always especially before
专门用于测试和安全的团队始终是uh，尤其是之前
these hard-fought upgrades are heavily testing the clients. So first of all, there is the
这些艰苦的升级正在对客户进行大量测试。所以首先，有
Ethereum test, which is just a basic state-transition test, like basic sets of tests
以太坊测试，这只是一个基本的状态过渡测试，例如基本测试集
that the client should pass. This is coming from the original Ethereum design with
客户应该通过。这来自原始的以太坊设计
only one layer, not the consensus layer, so it tests just the execution layer,
只有一层，而不是共识层，因此它仅测试执行层，
Similar to execution spec tests, which are based on the specs.
类似于基于规格的执行规格测试。
Very interesting, very important is Hive, the one in the middle, lower middle.
非常有趣，非常重要的是蜂巢，一个在中间，下中间。
Hive is an end-to-end harness tool.
Hive是一种端到端线束工具。
It's like a huge tool which lets you do everything.
这就像一个巨大的工具，可以让您做所有事情。
it you can spin networks with different clients in it and run them together through different tests
它可以与其中的不同客户端旋转网络，并通过不同的测试一起运行它们
uh there are many simulations that you can run using it and uh it creates real complex and uh
嗯，有许多模拟可以使用它运行，并且它创造了真正的复杂和嗯
strong uh testing tool uh kurtosis is uh also lets you like create a local test net with different
强大的UH测试工具UH Kurtosis uh还可以让您喜欢创建一个不同的本地测试网
clients and then there is fuzzing which is like uh heavily testing different edge cases
客户，然后是模糊的，就像在大量测试不同的边缘案例一样
Mario's doing the fuzzing of different parts of the clients,
马里奥正在对客户的不同部分进行模糊，
and then other testing, like benchmarking, stress testing,
然后其他测试，例如基准测试，应力测试，
making sure that what if we deploy a huge amount of
确保如果我们部署大量
validators or a huge amount of this or that,
验证者或大量的验证者或
does it go belly up, does it survive?
它会腹部倒闭吗，它可以生存吗？
What if it create huge block,
如果它创造了巨大的障碍怎么办，
can the client process it?
客户可以处理吗？
Testing the actual performance,
测试实际性能，
the features of the client.
客户的功能。
Shadow forks are very important testing parts.
阴影叉是非常重要的测试零件。
These are like kind of the DevOps kind of like more high-level testing in a way that, like, we take part of the network.
这些就像Devops一样，就像我们参与网络的方式一样，就像更高级的测试一样。
We take, like, 20 clients which are synced to mainnet, and then we put them through a hard fork as they will go in production.
我们采用的是20个客户，这些客户与主网同步，然后我们将其固定在生产中。
But they just create, like, their own fork network.
但是他们只是创建自己的叉子网络。
and we see what happened.
我们看到发生了什么。
We see in this case on the left,
在这种情况下，我们在左边看到
you see that like two or four of these clients
您会看到这些客户中的两个或四个
or client pairs went down during the shadow fork.
或客户对在阴影叉期间下降。
And yeah, client test, of course,
是的，客户测试当然
like clients are testing their clients themselves
就像客户自己测试客户一样
and with like continuous integration,
并像连续整合一样
they can test every PR, every commit to the code.
他们可以测试每个PR，每个对代码的提交。
So to reiterate on what I described here,
因此，要重申我在这里描述的内容，
how Ethereum was created and how,
以太坊的创建方式以及如何
maybe everything that was outside of Ethereum,
也许以太坊以外的一切，
but how these processes in Ethereum work
但是以太坊中的这些过程如何工作
is that we start with some ideas, some general description,
是我们从一些想法开始，一些一般描述，
which then needs to be researched for its feasibility,
然后需要研究其可行性，
for the effectivity.
为了有效性。
we figure out how to make this idea actually real in some doable practical way uh based on that it's
我们弄清楚如何以某种可行的实用方式使这个想法实际上是根据的
specified uh the specification are implemented in software the software gets tested and then
指定的uh规范是在软件中实现的，该软件被测试，然后
it gets rejected because nobody likes it uh it's really a thing that um uh some of course like many
它被拒绝了，因为没人喜欢它，这确实是一件像许多人一样的事情
of these things are adopted running on mainnet but it's it's it's really a thing in if you are
这些东西在mainnet上被采用，但这确实是一件事情
if you are ethereum researcher developer you can spend literally years like i know people who spend
如果您是以太坊研究人员开发人员，您可以像我知道的那样花几年的时间
like three years or more working on a single thing single upgrade for ethereum which is really good
就像三年或更长时间的单一升级以太坊的单一升级一样，这真的很好
and useful but it has some edge cases or something so it's still not adopted it's still being rejected
而且有用，但是它有一些边缘案例或其他东西，因此它仍然没有被采用
and you have to come back you come back from well any point on this chart you might it rejected and
而且您必须回来您从此图表上的任何一点回来，您可能会拒绝，并且
go back to researching your idea you might fail at testing and you need to fix your implementation or
回到研究您的想法您可能未能进行测试，您需要修复您的实施或
the implementation doesn't follow the specs properly and you need to you need to um you need
实施不正确遵循规格，您需要您需要
to fix that so yeah it's like a very uh uh iterative cycle like it's always always one uh two
要解决这个问题，是的，就像一个非常迭代的循环一样，就像它总是一个uh两个
step forward one step back let's say uh and it's not it's not easy so now you might ask like okay
向前迈出一步，假设嗯，这并不容易，所以现在您可能会问好的
how this whole process with all of these different developers all these different teams uh works uh
所有这些不同的开发人员的整个过程如何工作
So I showed you like here, the different clients, right?
所以我向您展示了在这里，不同的客户，对吗？
There are five, there are, I'm sorry,
有五个，很抱歉，
seven clients on this page, five clients here.
此页面上有七个客户，这里有五个客户。
I mentioned some others which are being developed.
我提到了正在开发的其他一些。
So we have these testing teams, client teams, research teams.
因此，我们拥有这些测试团队，客户团队，研究团队。
Altogether, it's basically like 20 different teams,
总的来说，它基本上就像20个不同的团队，
around 20 different teams,
大约20个不同的团队，
and like maybe 200 plus people from these different teams
就像这些不同团队的200个人一样
and independently working on Ethereum.
并独立于以太坊工作。
So the question is how they all coordinate,
所以问题是他们如何协调，
How it's possible that we ship, how it's possible that we agree on what Ethereum is supposed to look like.
我们有可能发货，我们有可能就以太坊的外观达成共识。
So first, there are many parts to it.
因此，首先，有很多部分。
I'm going to start from the bottom.
我将从底部开始。
ETH research, it's a forum where people post their ideas.
ETH研究，这是一个论坛，人们发布了他们的想法。
People post something coming in these first two categories.
人们在前两个类别中发布一些内容。
So, when I see some problem or some missing feature in Ethereum or something that should
因此，当我看到以太坊中的某些问题或一些缺失的功能或某些内容
be changed, tweaked, I can post it on the research where I show outcome of my research,
可以更改，调整，我可以将其发布在我的研究结果的研究中，
my ideas and the way that I tested it, the way that I proposed it, and it gets heavily
我的想法和测试方式，我提出的方式，它变得越来越大
discussed there.
在那里讨论。
These community proposals are then formalized as EIPs that I mentioned before.
然后，这些社区建议被正式为我之前提到的EIP。
The EIPs have their discussion under EAT magicians forums, another forum which is not discussing
EIP在Eat Magicians论坛下进行讨论，这是另一个没有讨论的论坛
it like general research ideas, yes, like EAT research, but specific EIPs and the way
就像一般研究思想一样，是的，就像饮食研究一样，但是特定的EIP和方式
they are specified.
他们被指定。
And then like EIP, it's a process about the EIPs themselves.
然后像EIP一样，这是关于EIP本身的过程。
So we also have like community, you know, editing the EIPs and making sure that, you
因此，我们也喜欢社区，您知道，编辑EIP并确保您
know, they make sense, they are formally correct.
知道，它们很有意义，它们正式正确。
This is done mostly by CAD Heredity Community.
这主要由CAD遗传社区完成。
They also have this peep at EIP series with videos giving a space to like EIP champions
他们在EIP系列中还带有视频的窥视，为EIP冠军提供了一个空间
to talk about their proposals.
谈论他们的建议。
So these are the forum discussions, the public discussions, a lot of discussion, a lot of
因此，这些是论坛讨论，公众讨论，很多讨论，很多
coordination is happening in R&D Discord.
协调正在研发不和谐中。
The R&D Discord is a server similar to our EPS one where people from many different teams
研发不和谐是类似于我们的EPS的服务器，来自许多不同团队的人
participate in discussion and updates and so on.
参加讨论和更新等。
Here on the R&D Discord is also where you can see a release of the dev calls.
在研发和不和谐上，您也可以在其中看到开发呼叫的发布。
So now there are different calls of developers, which are regular and maybe the most important part of this to follow if you want to learn about what's happening now in Ethereum.
因此，现在有不同的开发人员呼叫，如果您想了解以太坊中正在发生的事情，则是规则的，也许是最重要的部分。
So there are what we call ACD calls, the all-core devs.
因此，我们称之为ACD调用，即全核开发人员。
And these are focused on either execution layer or consensus layer, always on Thursday, like today.
这些都集中在执行层或共识层上，总是像今天一样。
So later today, there will be a call with maybe 50 people, representatives of different teams, discussing the current changes, the actions before the hard work.
因此，今天晚些时候，将会与可能有50个人，不同团队的代表进行电话，讨论当前的变化以及辛勤工作之前的行动。
So right now, the biggest topic is planning of the upcoming DENEP upgrade.
因此，目前，最大的话题是计划即将进行的DENEP升级。
And I believe today was the deadline for the client releases.
我相信今天是客户发行的截止日期。
So if somebody didn't, so on these calls, they agreed, like, okay, this is a reasonable deadline for us of each of these teams to ship this feature.
因此，如果有人没有，那么在这些电话中，他们同意，好吧，这是我们每个团队运输此功能的合理截止日期。
So they talk and they are able to coordinate using this.
因此，他们交谈，并且能够使用此问题进行协调。
and then there are like not all core devs but like specific uh feature uh like calls dedicated
然后并非所有核心开发人员，而是像特定的uh功能一样
to implementers of specific feature like we saw with 4844 or when we test uh test nets
到我们看到4844或测试UH测试网时的特定功能的实施者
or missing t there uh when uh it was garily deprecated and and uh we were deploying the test
或在uh上丢失了uh，uh被贬低了，而我们正在部署测试
nets or eof was a feature which was discussed like this uh there's also wallet devs coordination call
网或EOF是一个像这样讨论的功能
for like standards for wallets which is a bit outside of the protocol but worth mentioning
对于钱包的类似标准，这有点超出协议，但值得一提
uh so yeah uh these are these are the regular calls it's it's worth following and it's it's
嗯，是的，呃，这些是普通的电话，值得关注，这是
a it's it's here where the coordination actually happens where people like some ideas and it's not
a是在这里，协调实际上是在人们喜欢某些想法而不是的情况下发生的
that simple you know like people uh i would i would say argue because like it's civilized
你知道的那个简单的人，我会说争论，因为就像它是文明的
discussion but still it can be a passionate discussion which takes sometimes takes weeks
讨论，但仍然可能是一个充满激情的讨论，有时需要花费数周的时间
and months before some some something is agreed on and uh that's very important that people come
几个月前，几个月来达成共识，嗯，这很重要的是人们来
from different perspectives different backgrounds with different teams voicing their opinions and
从不同的角度来看，不同的背景与不同的团队发表意见和
this is all public you can it's streamed on youtube and you can even participate by joining
这是所有公众，您可以在YouTube上流式传输，甚至可以通过加入来参与
the r d discord so anybody can voice their opinion about the ethereum core uh yeah this is coordinated
R D DISCORD，因此任何人都可以对以太坊核心表达自己的看法，是的，这是协调的
it uh in the pm repo so you can see all of these calls uh they are scheduled they are the topics
它在PM存储库中，因此您可以看到所有这些调用，呃，它们是安排的，它们是主题
to be discussed there you can propose a topic and so on uh you can see the recordings the uh uh the
要在那里讨论您可以提出一个主题，因此，在嗯，您可以看到录音
record of all of the previous uh meetings in uh the ethereum slash pm project repository
以太坊斜线PM项目存储库中所有以前所有UH会议的记录
this is how it looks like uh one a life hack is that if you are uh uh if you are pretending you
这就是看起来像一个生命的人，如果你是假装的话，如果你是呃
working you know somewhere you can just put this on your screen the youtube call and act like it's
工作在某个地方，您知道您可以将其放在屏幕上的YouTube电话，然后像它一样行动
uh you already call um and yeah in addition to this the people also meet in person uh because
嗯，您已经打电话给UM，是的，除此之外，人们还亲自见面，因为
sometimes it's you know better to talk face to face and just figure out like uh things hands-on
有时候，您知道面对面说话，然后弄清楚就像动手一样
uh and this is a famous picture where uh people are clapping to the first uh merge like this is
呃，这是一张著名的图片，嗯，人们正在拍手到第一个uh合并
the first time that the merge was actually tested uh actually tried implement uh implemented in
第一次实际测试了合并实际上尝试实现UH实施的UH
in greece uh it was 20 20 20 i think uh no no 2021 and then it was this was last year a year ago in
在希腊，是20 20 20，我想呃，没有2021，那是去年一年前
austria where uh people were finishing uh withdrawals working on 4844 again like 100
奥地利的人们在4844年再次完成UH撤回工作，例如100
people meeting uh in different sessions uh uh focusing on on uh shipping the the next thing
人们在不同的会议上与uh见面的人uh UH专注于UH运送下一件事
um so yeah that's that's how the developers coordinated but the question is like okay what
嗯，是的，这就是开发人员的协调方式，但问题就像还可以
these developers are actually developing what they are working on where is it coming from
这些开发人员实际上正在开发他们正在从事的工作
well there are researchers and uh people proposing these these new upgrades new features uh and uh
好吧，有研究人员和uh人们提出这些新升级的新功能，UH和UH
there is a some loose road map of what is happening in theorem right now when i say
当我说的时，有一个宽松的路线图
lose road map you maybe saw this uh this is uh like the road map uh from uh uh vitalik who
丢失路线图，您也许看到了这是UH的路线图，UH Vitalik的路线图
makes this beautiful beautiful chart however uh this is not like you know the definitive
使这张美丽的图表使您不知道确定的
ethereum roadmap this is not like this has to happen this will happen this is just uh enumeration
以太坊路线图，这并不像这样，这将发生这只是枚举
of the current things being worked on the current ideas uh the the landscape of the r d right now
目前正在处理当前想法的事物中，现在是R D的景观
because it changes and uh maybe we'll figure out that some of these boxes actually don't
因为它改变了，嗯，也许我们会弄清楚其中一些盒子实际上没有
fit the ethereum vision or come with some trade-offs and so on as we go along um
适合以太坊的视野或进行一些权衡，等等，我们继续前进
so to give you an idea what is happening right now again like what i said about the boxes before uh
因此，让您知道现在再次发生的事情，就像我对盒子所说的话一样
in my chart of my visualization of the Ethereum there again you can deep dive and become expert
在我对以太坊的可视化图表中，您可以再次深入研究并成为专家
in any of these boxes basically uh and uh the first big part is the merge um which was successfully
在这些盒子中的任何一个基本上都是呃，嗯，第一大部分是成功的合并
finished we merged the Ethereum with the proof of stake however there are some upgrades to the
完成的我们将以太坊与股份证明合并，但是有一些升级
uh to the proof of stake uh like single-fold finality making faster finalization so we can
嗯，托有股份的证明，呃，就像单折，最终确定速度更快，以便我们可以
still improve the the closest protocol um the search uh in this case is focused on scalable
在这种情况下，搜索uh仍在改进最接近的协议
scalability so to uh enable throughput of more transaction uh that includes implementing
可伸缩性因此，uh启用更多交易的吞吐量，包括实施
peer-to-peer implementing a data availability sharding and the 4244 the blobs which are coming
点对点实现数据可用性碎片和4244即将到来的斑点
in the upcoming upgrade uh scourge is focused on economics that's miv part uh so the maximum
在即将到来
minor extractable value uh which uh which has some issues it can cause some issues in the network
uh的次要可提取价​​值uh，哪些问题可能会引起网络中的某些问题
like uh uh like centralization or um or problem for most building blocks so there are there are
就像大多数构建基块一样
proposals like uh protocol builder separation enshrined in protocol um and there's some
诸如UH协议构建器分离之类的建议um，还有一些
censorship resistance and so on uh with the also uh also there is mentioned uh staking economics
审查制度等等，uh uh也有提到的uh Staking经济
it's also like uh proof of stake improvements of uh exploring how we can use the uh the
这也就像UH的股份改进证明UH探索我们如何使用UH
economics there more effectively uh diverge is the vertical tries so as i mentioned before the
在那里的经济学更有效地分歧是垂直的尝试，因此，正如我之前提到的
current state of it theorem is the merkel patricia uh three which is uh like one way
当前状态定理是默克尔·帕特里夏（Merkel Patricia UH）
we have been doing it for 10 years but now there is this proposal in testing in development for
我们已经做了10年了，但是现在有一个关于开发测试的建议
a vector commitment miracle trees which are using vectors uh to create a tree which enables like uh
矢量承诺奇迹树，它使用向量uh创建了一个启用uh的树
witnesses and more simple proofs like it proves which can be
证人和更简单的证据证明了可以是
uh which can enable stateless or uh much lighter clients so more scalability um
嗯，可以启用无状态或更轻松的客户，因此更大的可扩展性UM
purge uh means getting rid of the technical debt and uh all the data so like there is bunch of
清除意味着摆脱技术债务和所有数据，所以像一堆
state bunch of old data which is never going to be used but the clients the nodes are required
一堆永远不会使用的旧数据，但客户端需要节点
to hold it um so we can we can actually have uh uh some improvements to to uh have the old data
要持有它，所以我们可以实际上可以对UH有一些改进，uh拥有旧数据
expire uh splurge is there uh the rest of it like evm improvements uh vdfs etc yeah so this is like
过期的uh挥霍在那里，其余的像EVM改进uh vdfs等
a short overview to give you an idea what's happening in different tracks different urges
简短的概述，让您了解不同的曲目中发生的事情不同的冲动
of ethereum um ultimately all of this is trying to fight this monster of a triangle
以太坊最终，所有这些都试图与这个三角形的怪物作斗争
maybe you saw this before and this is the problem of uh the blockchain itself because
也许您以前看到了，这是区块链本身的问题，因为
well the whole point of ethereum is to be this distributed decentralized network which uh which
好吧，以太坊的重点是要成为这个分布式的分散网络
is secure and uh to enable decentralization what i said before to run one of these clients to
是安全的，可以使我以前说的权力下放，以使这些客户之一
actually use ethereum in a trustless and secure way you need to run one of these clients and that
实际使用以太坊以一种无信任和安全的方式运营这些客户之一，并且
can take uh to verify the uh so it means that you need to actually verify the transaction the data
可以使用UH验证UH，因此这意味着您需要实际验证数据
in the network so if i want to use ethereum i use my own client which verified all of the history
在网络中，因此，如果我想使用以太坊，我会使用自己的客户端来验证所有历史记录
the current state. However, it takes hundreds of gigabytes of data and tens or hundreds of hours
当前状态。但是，需要数百千兆字节的数据和数十个小时
of the CPU time. So it's pretty heavy to run on your laptop. And if we put more data, which needs
CPU时间。因此，在笔记本电脑上运行非常沉重。如果我们放置了更多数据，哪个需要
to be verified, of course, it becomes more and more heavier. And if we keep doing this, it becomes
当然要验证，它变得越来越重。如果我们继续这样做，那就变成了
exponentially heavy and ultimately there would be only a few uh few single single uh institutions
成倍沉重，最终只有几个单一的UH机构
running these nodes and that would be centralizing that would uh give us a single point of failure so
运行这些节点，这将是集中的，这会给我们带来单个失败点，所以
ethereum needs to be decentralized ethereum is limiting itself it's limiting it's on-chain uh
以太坊需要被分散的以太坊正在限制它，它限制了它的链子
activity to the point where you can run this one of these clients on a raspberry pi on like very
活动到您可以在Raspberry Pi上运行这些客户中的一个
cheap low-powered 100 200 bucks device plus ssd uh so so yeah uh this is the point and now what
便宜的低功率100200磅设备加上SSD呃，所以是的，这就是重点，现在是什么
we what these researchers are fighting is uh of course different problems but this is a big part
我们这些研究人员的战斗当然是不同的问题，但这是很大的一部分
of it to be able to run ethereum trustlessly uh and at the same time allow more data being
它能够无信任地运行以太坊，同时允许更多数据
processed which is kind of oxymoron kind of in a dilemma here but uh there are ways uh outlined
加工在这里的困境中有点像矛盾，但是有uh概述的方式
here that can improve it diverge the search um yeah the purge uh which are focused on this and
在这里可以改善它的搜索um是的
yeah so there are there are many different improvements to it here many different things
是的，所以这里有许多不同的改进
that we can we can fix and uh ultimately uh you might think that well it's kind of an infinite
我们可以解决并最终可以修复，您可能会认为这是一个无限的
fight it's an infant garden right uh it's uh never ending always growing always to be trimmed and
打架它是一个婴儿花园，嗯
maintained garden and uh that's somewhat true like i believe that ethereum core protocol is a garden
维护花园和嗯，这有些真实，就像我相信以太坊核心协议是花园
which always needs some gardeners some people to take care of it uh and right now it needs to
总是需要一些园丁，有些人来照顾它，现在需要
expand and fix many things and you know uh fix uh a big bunch of it's uh issues to get to some
扩展和修复许多事情，您知道您可以解决很多问题，以获取一些问题
better state however at one point there will be beautiful garden which only needs maintenance
但是，更好的状态在某一时刻将有美丽的花园，只需要维护
at that moment that would be ossification uh that's something that i hope i believe we are
在那一刻那是骨化的嗯，我希望我相信我们是
aiming for to like some more of a final design with uh ethereum uh not allowing any more major
旨在与Uh Ethereum更喜欢一些最终设计
changes only doing minor maintenance of updates so that's that's the ideal endgame here uh however
更改仅对更新进行少量维护，因此这是理想的最终游戏，但是
still it's an infant corner which uh never really ends uh but it would be beautiful if we get to
仍然是一个婴儿角落
this point of the ossified not really changing ethereum uh that would be it would be a beautiful
骨化的这一点并没有真正改变以太坊嗯，那将是一个美丽的
world isn't it and vitalik would be happy we need to we need to make him happy guys so
世界不是这样，维塔利克会很高兴我们需要让他快乐的家伙，所以
yeah if you are excited about this if you're excited about ethereum about all of the this
是的，如果您对所有这些都感到兴奋，请对此感到兴奋
progress happening uh the different clients development uh the the research uh you are
进展正在发生不同的客户发展，呃，您是研究
in the right place you are in the epf study group where you can learn all about it uh but yeah what
在正确的位置，您在EPF研究小组中可以学习所有有关它的知识，但是是的
now what you can uh what you can do when you when you get here so i believe i provided a lot
现在，当您到达这里时，您可以做什么，所以我相信我提供了很多
of resources uh right now you can uh see the pro some resources from this presentation i believe
我现在可以从本演示文稿中看到一些资源的资源。
all of them are in the uh uh in the wiki there uh in the week one wiki and when i say resources
他们所有人都在Wiki中的UH中，一个Wiki，当我说资源时
i also mean just you know the pictures the charts that i show you and are uh explaining different
我的意思是，只是您知道我向您展示的图表，并且正在解释不同的图片
parts of the clients you can start diving into these you can learn more about it find more
您可以开始潜入这些客户的一部分您可以了解更多有关它的信息
relevant related connected documents and share them come to share them on discord and
相关相关的连接文档并分享它们以在不和谐和
update update them in the wiki so you can uh uh you can um uh find what makes you more interested
在Wiki中更新它们，以便您可以找到使您更感兴趣的原因
what's your niche what's your expertise uh and and contribute uh like yeah something that i
您的利基是您的专业知识是什么
didn't mention properly before so when you when you see this this monster of a machine all of
在您看到这台机器的怪物时，没有正确提及
these different uh uh roadmap points or if you see the ethereum uh uh with so many parts here
这些不同的uh路线图点，或者如果您看到以太坊，呃，这里有很多部分
and the testing and so on there is not a single person who would be expert in all of these there
而且测试等
There is not a single person who would be a developer of the whole Ethereum,
没有一个人会成为整个以太坊的开发人员，
but it's always being an expert in some of these parts
但这一直是其中一些部分的专家
or like an execution or consensus.
或像执行或共识一样。
So that's what the modularity allows us to like focus on.
这就是模块化使我们喜欢关注的目标。
What do you like the more?
您更喜欢什么？
What do you find the most important, exciting?
您发现最重要，令人兴奋的是什么？
And you are, maybe you have some talents for.
而且，也许您有一些才华。
So yeah, focus on that.
是的，专注于此。
Find your niche and contribute.
找到您的利基市场并做出贡献。
Find these resources, write more documentation
找到这些资源，写更多文档
and upload it to the wiki,
并将其上传到Wiki，
open a PR, learn how to use Git,
打开公关，学习如何使用git，
learn how to actually contribute
了解如何实际贡献
to the open source projects
到开源项目
by contributing to our free open wiki.
通过为我们的免费开放Wiki做出贡献。
There are already some PRs open.
已经有一些公关开放。
If you are here, guys who opened it,
如果您在这里，那些打开它的家伙，
thank you so much.
太感谢了。
It will be, you know, slowly reviewed
你知道，会慢慢审查
that you can see the PRs
您可以看到PR
which has been opened
已经打开的
and contribute there.
并在那里做出贡献。
Maybe give your, add some content there
也许给您，在那里添加一些内容
or add your idea like,
或添加您的想法，
okay, maybe this should be written differently, etc.
好的，也许应该以不同的方式写这件事，等等。
So yeah, come to contribute.
是的，开始贡献。
And yeah, you can, at this point, we did like four EPF cohorts.
是的，您可以在这一点上喜欢四个EPF队列。
And you can find projects from all the previous cohorts in the same GitHub organization that we use for the wiki.
您可以在我们用于Wiki的同一GitHub组织中的所有先前人群中找到项目。
So in the it protocol follows cohort four, cohort three, in the slash project, the project directory, you see all of the projects that has been worked on.
因此，在IT协议中，遵循第四个队列，第三个队列，在Slash Project，项目目录中，您会看到所有已在进行的项目。
by the previous follows.
按照以下内容。
And now what I mentioned
现在我提到的
at the beginning
在开始
that this program is inspired by EPF
该程序受EPF的启发
is because these people
是因为这些人
spend the first weeks,
花前几周，
first months of the fellowship program
奖学金计划的头几个月
learning about the protocol
了解协议
and about their niche,
关于他们的利基，
about their domain.
关于他们的领域。
And if you read their projects,
如果您阅读了他们的项目，
if you read,
如果您阅读，
they write weekly updates.
他们每周写更新。
You can see bi-weekly
您可以每两周看到
or weekly documents
或每周文件
written by many talented people
由许多才华横溢的人撰写
who've been learning about Ethereum
谁一直在学习以太坊
or different parts of it.
或其中的不同部分。
you can you can see their learning curve you can see what they've been working on and uh maybe
您可以看到他们的学习曲线，您可以看到他们一直在做什么，也许
find the resources that they are they are mentioning there bring them to the wiki learn
找到他们在那里提到的资源，将他们带到Wiki学习
from them so you can follow follow their paths because that's why they created it that's why we
从他们那里，您可以遵循他们的道路，因为这就是他们创建它的原因，这就是为什么我们
kept it open public so you can all study it you can uh learn about their projects and uh their
让它公开公开，以便您可以学习它，您可以了解他们的项目并
their journey yeah and uh yeah i believe that's that's all folks uh there is uh that's that's
他们的旅程是的，是的，是的，我相信那是所有人
the week one presentation uh right now there are already resources up for the week two uh next week
一周的演示文稿UH现在已经有了第二周的资源
we will be diving into the execution layer with light plant but before that like please check out
我们将使用轻型植物潜入执行层，但在此之前请查看
more of the resources from the week one and some pre-reading for the week two part and yeah it's
第一周的更多资源和本周两部分的一些预读，是的
been 90 minutes, I used all of my time, oh my god, yeah, so sorry to keep you up so long, guys,
已经90分钟了，我所有的时间都花了很多时间
so let's take maybe five minutes for some questions, if there are any, and let's wrap it up,
因此，如果有的话，让我们花五分钟的时间来解决一些问题，然后将其包裹起来，
yeah, do we have any questions in the, oh, thank you so much, Josh, for sending all of the,
是的，哦，哦，非常感谢，乔什，我们有任何疑问，
uh all of the all of the um uh links so here uh the screenshot that this this monster of a markdown
嗯，所有的所有UM uh链接，所以在这里屏幕截图，这是一个降价的怪物
table that he uh josh uh shared there it's uh um uh it's um uh all these weekly updates so you can
表明他在那里分享了他的uh uh uh嗯，嗯，嗯，所有这些每周更新，所以你可以
see what a person in the slash project you can see what project the person has been working on
查看斜线项目中的一个人，您可以看到该人一直在从事的项目
and if you're interested like i don't know uh contribution to lighthouse client
如果您感兴趣，就像我不知道对灯塔客户的贡献
uh creation of stealth addresses uh a creation of new beacon api so if you are interested in like
uh的隐身创建解决了一个新的信标API的创建，因此，如果您对此感兴趣
different projects there you can see what's been the journey of the person in this weekly updates
那里的不同项目您可以在本周更新中看到该人的旅程
yeah ah yeah awesome uh
是的，真棒嗯
If there are any questions, any more comments, feel free to go on.
如果有任何疑问，还有更多评论，请随时继续前进。
I think we still can have some time.
我认为我们还有一些时间。
Looks like there's a few people typing right now, but I'm not seeing any questions
看起来现在有几个人在打字，但我没有看到任何问题
come through at the moment.
目前来。
So, history of it's the F missing it before it's there.
因此，它的历史是F之前缺少F。
Just what I was going on about.
正是我要做的。
No, I don't, I'm just, I was just texting Stolman yesterday, he's a friend of mine,
不，我不，我只是，我昨天只是在发短信，他是我的朋友，
and I'm biased here, I pushed for the F part there.
我在这里有偏见，我推向了那里的f部分。
Anyway, if there are no questions right now, my camera doesn't work.
无论如何，如果现在没有问题，我的相机不起作用。
No, that's horrible.
不，这太可怕了。
Anyway, if there are no questions right now,
无论如何，如果现在没有问题，
please just feel free to ping me anytime in the Discord.
请随时随时在不和谐中使用我。
I'm here for you guys.
我在这里为你们。
It's morning for me, so the rest of the day,
对我来说是早晨，所以一天的余下时间，
I guess I'm ready to answer your questions.
我想我准备回答您的问题。
Feel free to put them in this thread or in a corresponding channel.
可以随意将它们放入此线程或相应的通道中。
On the left, you see the protocol wiki part with different parts of it.
在左侧，您会看到协议Wiki部分，其中具有不同部分的部分。
So feel free to ask there if you have anything.
因此，请随时询问您是否有什么。
Yeah.
是的。
Thank you so much for your time.
非常感谢您的宝贵时间。
I really appreciate it.
我真的很感激。
So many of you showed up.
你们中的许多人出现了。
I had to wake up for this, so I really appreciate it.
我不得不为此醒来，所以我真的很感激。
I would like to wake up somewhere or at least, like,
我想醒来的某个地方或至少，就像
have a public talk for so many people this early.
这么早就对这么多人进行公开谈话。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Thanks so much, Mario.
非常感谢，马里奥。
That was a great talk once again, and we definitely got it recorded this time.
这再次是一次很棒的演讲，这次我们肯定会记录下来。
So, yeah, for those of you who didn't catch it either of these two times,
所以，是的，对于那些没有抓住这两次的人，
you can see it on the recording, and we will be back next Monday
您可以在录音中看到它，我们将在下周一回来
for the second week's content with LiteClient on the execution layer.
在执行层上的第二周内容中，列克莱恩的内容。
yeah thank you guys see you on monday 4 p.m utc i believe yeah uh awesome yeah thanks
是的，谢谢你们在星期一下午4点见到你，我相信是的，太棒了，谢谢
all right
好的
see you around
再见
you
你